if you go on social media seedor are
如果你浏览社交媒体，会发现种子要么
toxic seedor are going to give you
有毒，要么会导致
Alzheimer's seedor are going to give you
阿尔茨海默病，要么会导致
cancer but I've done lots of research
癌症。但我做了很多研究，
and there is absolutely no evidence to
完全没有证据
show seed alls are harmful actually
表明种子有害，实际上
they're beneficial for our health and
它们对我们的健康有益，这一点
I'll come back to that but the problem
我稍后会详细解释。但问题
is that there is so much misinformation
是，
out there about what we eat how we eat
关于我们吃什么、怎么吃
and how it affects our health so let's
以及饮食如何影响健康，存在太多错误信息。所以，让我们来深入探讨一下。
go into all of that Dr Sarah Barry is a
莎拉·贝瑞博士是一位
renowned nutrition scientist and
著名的营养科学家和
Professor with over 20 years of research
教授，拥有超过20年的研究经验。
her work has reshaped how we think about
她的研究成果重塑了我们对
food metabolism and gut health Dr Sarah
食物代谢和肠道健康的认知。莎拉·
Berry we have a lot to get through yes
贝瑞博士，我们有很多内容要讲。是的，
so let's start with the food Matrix
让我们从食物矩阵开始。食物矩阵
that's so important because you can have
非常重要，因为
two foods with identical labeling same
两种标签相同的食物，即使
nutrients and calorie value can have
营养成分和热量值相同，它们对
how you metabolize our food and how it
人体代谢和
impacts Downstream health effects
后续健康的影响也可能截然不同，这
depending on how that food has been
取决于食物的
processed now we also know the timing of
加工方式。我们都知道，
when we eat is really important for
进食时间也很重要。
example we found that snacking after
例如，我们发现晚上9点后吃零食
9:00 was associated with unfavorable
与…… 不良的
Health outcomes the worst kind of fat
健康后果，
around your belly for example this was
例如腹部脂肪堆积，
even if you were snacking on healthy
即使你吃的是健康
snacks really and we also know that on
零食，也难以避免。我们还知道，
average if you change the speed in which
平均而言，如果你将进食速度提高
you eat your food by 20% you reduce your
20%，就能减少
calorie intake by about 15% but where it
约15%的卡路里摄入。但
gets really interesting is there's
真正有趣的是，有
evidence to show if you chew your food
证据表明，咀嚼食物
40 times versus 15 times it can result
40次与15次相比，可能会导致更严重的后果。
in and then there's the menopause we've
此外，我们还研究了更年期，其中
the most exciting things is that there
最令人兴奋的发现之一是，有一些
is principles which can reduce symptoms
原则可以减轻
by about 35% and so they are
约35%的症状。
this has always blown my mind a little
这一点一直让我感到有些惊讶。
regularly haven't yet subscribed to the
经常收听我们节目的听众中，有53%还没有订阅。
show so could I ask you for a favor
所以，在节目开始之前，我想请你们帮个忙：
before we start if you like the show and
如果你喜欢我们的节目，
you like what we do here and you want to
喜欢我们所做的一切，并且想要
support us the free simple way that you
支持我们，最简单的方法就是
can do just that is by hitting the
点击“
Subscribe button and my commitment to
订阅”按钮。我向你们承诺，
you is if you do that then I'll do
如果你们订阅了，
everything in my power me and my team to
我和我的团队将竭尽全力
make sure that this show is better for
确保节目能够持续播出。 每周都为您带来更好的内容，
you every single week we'll listen to
我们会倾听
your feedback we'll find the guest that
您的反馈，找到
you want me to speak to and we'll
您想让我采访的嘉宾，并
continue to do what we do thank you so
继续做好我们一直在做的事情，非常感谢。
[Music]
[音乐]
Dr Sarah Berry can you give me a little
莎拉·贝瑞博士，您能否简要
bit of an overview over what You' spent
概述一下您过去
the last s of 25 years of your career
25年职业生涯中重点
focusing on and understanding yeah so
关注和理解的内容？好的，我
I've spent 25 years starting out in
花了25年的时间，最初专注于一个
quite specific area looking at how diet
非常具体的领域，研究饮食如何
impacts our cardiometabolic health so by
影响我们的心血管代谢健康。
this I mean lots of factors related to
我的意思是，很多与
cardiovascular disease like type 2
心血管疾病相关的因素，比如2型
diabetes our cholesterol our blood
糖尿病、胆固醇、血压和
pressure our inflammation and then uh
炎症。然后，
more recently I've been looking at how
最近我一直在研究如何将我们自身、我们
complexity of who we are what we eat how
吃什么、我们如何吃这些复杂的因素，以及这些因素如何
we eat um into how that actually impacts
影响
how we respond to food and the
我们对食物的反应和
helpfulness of a food um most of my
食物的益处。我的大部分
work's been done through running
工作都是通过开展
clinical trials so randomized control
临床试验完成的，也就是随机对照
clinical trials where I recruit various
临床试验。在这些试验中，我会招募不同的
people get them to eat various things do
人，让他们吃各种不同的食物，进行大量的
measurements and look at how a food or a
测量，观察某种食物、
nutrient or a diet might impact a
营养素或饮食如何影响
particular Health outcome and how many
特定的健康结果，以及有多少结果会受到影响。
lifestyle are you trying to piece
我们试图将健康和生活方式的各个组成部分
together to form this picture what are
拼凑起来，从而形成一幅完整的图景。
those pieces the key pieces are who you
这些组成部分是什么？关键部分之一是“你
are MH so that's one of the key pieces
是谁”，这是关键部分之一。
so by that I mean your genetics your
我的意思是，你的基因、你的
microbiome your age your sex your
微生物群、你的年龄、你的性别、你的
menopause status all of those kind of
更年期状态等等。
things the other is the food that you
另一个关键部分是你所
eat and when we think about food we need
吃的食物。当我们思考食物时，我们需要
to think about it beyond the traditional
超越传统的营养成分认知，
way that we thought about food in terms
比如包装上的标签：
labeling fat protein fiber carbohydrate
脂肪、蛋白质、纤维、碳水化合物。
but actually thinking about food in
实际上，我们应该从食物的角度来思考，
terms of the fact that on average each
平均每种
food has 70,000 different chemicals and
食物都含有7万种不同的化学物质，
these are contained within a very
这些物质存在于一个非常
complex food structure which we call
复杂的食物结构中，我们称之为
Food Matrix that modulates the impact
食物基质。食物基质调节着
that those chemicals and nutrients have
这些化学物质和营养成分的作用。这是
so that's the second thing that we need
我们需要考虑的第二点。
to think about so we've got who you are
我们已经有了“你是谁”、
the food that you're eating but the
你所吃的食物、
complexity of that food and then how you
食物的复杂性，以及
eat your food and by how you eat your
你的饮食方式。说到你的饮食方式，
food I'm thinking about your lifestyle
我指的是你的生活方式，比如
while I'm thinking about are you
你是否受到时差的影响，
jetlagged how much sleep did you have
你昨晚睡了多久等等。
which you're eating your food within a
你在一
meal or over the day how stressed are
餐或一天中进食的顺序、
you feeling um when did you do physical
你的压力水平、你何时进行体育
activity all of that also impacts how
锻炼等等，所有这些因素都会影响
you will respond to a food and then I
你对食物的反应。我
think the last piece of the puzzle is so
认为最后一点
important that as nutritional scientists
至关重要，但作为营养科学家，我们往往对此
I don't think we think about enough why
思考不足：
do you make the diet of choices that you
你为什么会做出这样的饮食选择？
make so why do you choose to have that
你为什么选择这些食物
for breakfast for lunch for dinner is it
作为早餐、午餐或晚餐？是
because it's part of your culture is it
因为这是你文化的一部分吗？是
because that's how you're just feeling
因为你当时的
emotion is it because you're sitting
情绪状态吗？还是因为你
with friends and it's part of that
和朋友在一起，这是
social experience MH I think we're at a
社交体验的一部分？我认为我们正处于
really exciting time in nutritional
营养研究领域一个激动人心的时期，
research because we're now able to
因为我们现在能够以
to before that's allowing us to put
前所未有的规模、广度、深度和精度收集数据，这使我们能够将
together all of those pieces of the
所有这些碎片拼凑起来，
puzzle to start to see a clearer picture
从而看到更清晰的图景。那么，
so let's go into all of that let's start
让我们深入探讨一下，首先来谈谈
with um the subject of the food Matrix
食物矩阵，
which is a a term I hadn't actually
这是一个我
heard before um in today what is the
今天之前从未听说过的术语。那么，什么是
food Matrix and why why do I need to
食物矩阵？它又为何如此重要？ 我为什么要
know about that so the food Matrix
了解食物结构？食物结构
simply puts the structure of food and
简单来说就是食物的组成结构，
it's really important because we know
这非常重要，因为我们知道
that food is so much more than just the
食物远不止
nutrients and chemicals it contains so
它所含的营养素和化学物质。
we know that food contains nutrients
我们知道食物含有
that people are very familiar with like
人们非常熟悉的营养素，比如
protein fat fiber carbohydrate we know
蛋白质、脂肪、纤维和碳水化合物。我们
that food also contains thousands of
也知道食物含有成千上万种
other chemicals many of these we call
其他化学物质，其中许多被称为
bioactives that you have heard of like
生物活性物质，你可能听说过，比如
polyphenols you know vitam minerals
多酚、维生素、矿物质
Etc but they're all encapsulated within
等等。它们都被包裹在
the structure of a food so think of an
食物的结构中。想想
apple versus Apple puree versus apple
苹果、苹果泥和苹果
juice they're all coming from the same
汁，它们都来自同一种
food but they have a different
食物，但它们的结构不同。
is because we know that food structure
食物结构之所以重要，是因为我们知道食物结构会
modulates the healthfulness of the
影响
chemicals and nutrients within the food
食物中化学物质和营养素的健康程度。
and it's really really relevant now it's
这一点
really relevant now because our food
现在非常重要，因为我们的食物
landscape has changed almost
格局发生了
unrecognized ibly to 50 100 200 years
翻天覆地的变化，与50、100甚至200年前相比，
ago we're now eating a lot of food where
我们现在吃的很多食物，其
food has changed and this is because we
食物结构都发生了改变。这是因为我们
use multiple different processing
使用了多种不同的加工
techniques
技术。
so in simple terms if I were to zoom in
简单来说，如果我…… 用
on a piece of food on a microscope y the
显微镜放大观察食物，你会发现
way that the the molecule of the food is
食物分子的
put together is now different to what it
组成方式与以往不同，
used to be and that's having an impact
而这正在影响
on my health so in simple terms it's
我的健康。简单来说，我们
changing often through processing the
经常通过加工改变
structure of the food now by processing
食物的结构。这种加工方式包括
it could be our own processing when we
我们自身的咀嚼过程，比如我们
chew a food we change the structure take
咀嚼食物时，食物的结构也会发生改变。以
a nut for example you have a whole nut
坚果为例，你有一个完整的坚果，
you chew it you break up the nut it goes
你咀嚼它，坚果就碎了，它
into your gastrointestinal tract it's
进入你的消化道，会被
broken down further we also change it
进一步分解。我们也会
using manual industrial techniques as
使用人工和工业技术来改变食物的结构，
well so we use techniques like grinding
比如研磨，
or we might use posterization for dairy
或者对乳制品进行膨化处理，
or you know Extrusion for some
或者对一些
carbohydrate rich foods we all of these
富含碳水化合物的食物进行挤压。所有这些
different techniques that also change
不同的技术都会改变
the food Matrix For Better or For Worse
食物的基质，无论好坏。
it's a double-edged sword right and I
这就像一把双刃剑，对吧？我
think this is what we need to remember
认为我们需要记住这一点：
that everyone's demonizing at the moment
现在每个人都在妖魔化
Ultra processed food you know it's
超加工食品，你知道，它正在
killing the nation 60% of our energy is
危害国民健康。我们60%的能量都
coming from a processed food yes we are
来自加工食品。是的，我们
eating too much unhealthy food much of
吃了很多不健康的食物，其中很多都
which has been heavily processed but
经过了深度加工。 食品
processing can also be used to our
加工也可以
benefit and we have to think why do we
造福我们，我们首先要思考的是，我们为什么要
even process food in the first place
加工食物？
well we process it to make edible mhm I
加工是为了使食物可食用。嗯，我
don't want to go and eat a rice grain
不想吃
that's not been cooked we make it safe I
没煮熟的米饭。我们加工是为了确保食物安全。我
want to drink pasteurized milk because I
想喝巴氏杀菌牛奶，因为我
know it's safer we want to make it
知道它更安全。我们加工是为了保证食物的
stable I think how long a can can last
稳定性。想想罐头食品的保质期，还有
and frozen vegetables versus fresh so
冷冻蔬菜和新鲜蔬菜的区别，这样可以
you're saving food waste we want to make
减少食物浪费。我们加工是为了让食物更
it taste good mhm um and we want to make
美味。嗯，我们还加工是为了
it convenient so there's all of these
方便。所以，
different reasons that we use food
我们使用食品
processing but when we think about the
加工的原因有很多。但是，当我们考虑食物
healthfulness of a food we need to think
的健康性时，我们需要
about it in terms of the processing
从加工
techniques that have been used as well
技术
as the nutrient composition we can't
和营养成分两个方面来考虑。
look at them in isolation in my opinion
在我看来，我们不能孤立地看待它们。
and this is what I've done a lot of
这也是我做了很多
research looking into and what has
研究的重点。
bad I think processing gone bad is when
我认为，加工不当是指
you've change the nutrient profile of a
改变了食物的营养成分，使其变得
food such that it is unhealthy so in
不健康。
simple terms it's too much saturated fat
简单来说，就是饱和脂肪过多、
too much salt um too little fiber too
盐过多、纤维过少等等。
little bioactives like polyphenols a
像多酚这样的生物活性物质，以及
food that is very energy dense so you
能量密度很高的食物，所以你
eat it really really quickly so you're
会吃得非常快，
eating too many calories you're eating
摄入过多的卡路里。你还没等
it before your hunger signals have got
饥饿信号到达
to your brain say w Stephen you've had
大脑，大脑还没来得及告诉你“
enough and there's great research that
够了”，你就吃完了。有很多研究一直在
has been looking at how processing can
探讨食物加工如何
affect your eating rate the energy
影响你的进食速度、
density of food the nutrient profile of
食物的能量密度和营养成分。
a food and that's where it can go wrong
这就是问题所在，
but where it can go right is you can
但好的方面在于，你可以
improve all of those things I've said
改善我刚才提到的所有这些方面，比如
the stability the safety of the food you
食物的稳定性、安全性，你
can also um increase the what we call BI
还可以提高我们所说的生物可
accessibility so the availability of
及性，也就是
some of the nutrients within a food as
食物中某些营养物质的可用性。
well okay so I've got some snacks over
好的，我
in the corner of the room here which um
在房间角落里放了一些零食，
I guess have been processed differently
我想它们的加工方式不同，所以对
as the consumer gosh these look
消费者的影响也不同。哇，这些看起来真
delicious oh I hope they're salt and
好吃！哦，我希望它们是盐
vinegar Pringles you're going to eat
醋味的品客薯片，你会吃的。
them look at this oh my gosh um so I've
看看这些，我的天哪！我
got some mixed nuts here and I've got
这里还有一些混合坚果、一些
some cookies some little pieces of
饼干、一些小块
chocolate and uh some crisps so you were
巧克力和一些薯片。 你刚才
talking about this processing something
提到，有些食物经过加工处理，让
so that I eat it faster and that it
我吃得更快，而且
doesn't like sort of satiate me or make
不会让我感到饱腹或
me feel hungry crisps We're a nation of
饥饿，比如薯片。我们国家的人都
lovers um when you saying that about
爱吃薯片。嗯，当你提到那种
something that makes you eat fast and
让你吃得很快，甚至
not realize that you've even eaten all
感觉不到已经吃完的食物​​时，我
crisps were the first thing that came to
第一个
mind for me I love a crisp you love a
想到的就是薯片。我爱薯片，你也爱薯片，
crisp we all love a crisp so I think all
我们都爱薯片。所以我觉得，薯片、
the chocolate the cookies you know if
巧克力和饼干这三种食物，如果和
compared to what would be a healthy food
健康食品相比，
they've all got less fiber MH they've
它们的纤维含量都比较低。
wonderful bioactives in them um um and
嗯，巧克力和饼干的糖分含量更高。它们不含很多有益的生物活性成分。而且，
then with the crisps depending on the
薯片的含盐量
type of crisp is probably quite high in
可能很高，具体取决于薯片的种类。
in salt but the chances are with those
但总的来说，这
three is that they are quite energy
三种食物的能量
dense so they have quite a lot of
密度都很高，
calories per gram which is partly
每克含有大量的卡路里，这部分是由于
because of uh the processing techniques
加工工艺造成的。
yet if you take a whole food like a nut
然而，如果你吃像坚果这样的天然食物，
yeah now they're actually very energy
它们的能量
dense so they're very high in fat
密度其实也很高。 它们脂肪含量高，
they're high in calories
热量也高，
but actually because they're in their
但实际上，因为它们保留了
original food Matrix how your body
天然食物的形态，所以身体对它们的
handles them is quite different to if
处理方式与加工食品截然不同。
you mentioned something about my brain
你刚才提到，我的大脑
takes a little while to figure out that
需要一些时间才能意识到自己
I've started eating yep so if I started
开始进食了。是的，所以如果我
smashing these crisps down now how long
现在开始猛吃这些薯片，
would it take my brain to realize that
我的大脑需要多久才能意识到
I'd started eating to sort of catch up
自己已经开始进食，
and make me feel hungry yeah so there's
并让我感到饥饿？是的，有
Lo lots of different mechanisms that
很多不同的机制会
impact how full we feel how hungry we
影响我们对食物的饱腹感和饥饿感。
different areas of our gut for example
例如，我们肠道的不同区域会释放不同的激素，这些激素会发出
that feedback signals to say either
反馈信号，告诉我们是
you're full or you're hungry on average
饱了还是饿了。平均
I would say it takes about 10 to 20
而言，饱腹感大约需要10到20
minutes for the fullness to really
分钟才能
properly kick in now you could easily
真正发挥作用。你完全可以在
before under that 20 minutes I wasn't
20分钟内吃完这些薯片，我之前也完全可以在20分钟内吃完。我之前并不
aware that there was a delay but it does
知道会有这种延迟，但这确实说得
make sense because there's certain foods
通，因为
that I used to eat like like Pringles
我以前经常吃一些零食，比如品客薯片、
and snacks and crisps and things like
薯片之类的。
that where I feel like I could eat two
我觉得我能一口气吃掉两
Tu tubes of the thing before my body
管这种薯片，我的身体
even um realize what was going on and
甚至还没反应过来发生了什么。
are they in some way designed to
它们是不是故意设计成这样，
encourage that speed of eating and so
鼓励人们快速进食？
there are many people who will say the
很多人会说，
food industry has specifically designed
食品工业特意设计了
these to make them firstly what we call
这些薯片，首先是为了让它们“
hyper palatable so to have the right mix
超级美味”，也就是让
of fat sugar you know carbohydrate Etc
脂肪、糖、碳水化合物等等达到合适的比例，
to make them really tasty and in this
让它们非常好吃，在这个
case salt as
例子里还加了盐。
um I don't think the food industry is
我不认为食品工业是
out there to get us I think that what
故意要坑害我们。我认为
the food industry were doing 50 years
50年前的食品工业
ago versus what they're doing now is
和现在的食品工业已经
quite different but some people say I'm
大不相同了。有些人说我
very naive I do believe the food
太天真了，但我相信食品
industry ultimately want to produce food
工业最终的目标是生产
that's safe but also healthy for us
安全又健康的食品。
that's probably an unpopular opinion but
这可能是一个不太受欢迎的观点，但
based on my interactions with the food
根据我与食品
industry I believe that however I do
工业的接触，我相信这一点。然而，我确实
believe that these crisps are there
认为这些薯片被
have been made to be flavorsome to be
设计得美味可口，让
palatable to you so that you do enjoy
你喜欢吃。
them now whether that's that you then go
至于你会不会因此而
and overeat
吃过量，
them I think is yes a byproduct of that
我认为是的，这是个副产品。但这
um now it's not it doesn't take 20
并不是说……
minutes for all of the fullness signals
饱腹感信号并非需要20分钟才能
to kick in because as soon as you start
完全发挥作用，因为一旦你开始
chewing something you start to release
咀嚼，就会释放
different hormones and different sensory
不同的激素，
characteristics of the food will also
食物的不同感官特性也会
trigger some sort of fullness but what
触发某种饱腹感。但
we do do know is that you have more of
我们知道的是，消化道下部有更多的
these fullness receptors saying hey
饱腹受体发出“嘿，
you're full lower down in your
你饱了”的信号。
gastrointestinal tract and so if you can
所以，如果
get food to the lower gastrointestinal
食物能够到达消化道下部，它就会发出“
tract that's when it says hey Steph
嘿，斯蒂芬，
you're full now and these heavily
你现在饱了”的信号。你手里这些高度
processed snacks that you've got
加工的零食
here would be typically absorbed higher
通常会在
up the gastrointes because kind of the
消化道上部被吸收，因为大部分的
hard work's been done and yet when
加工工作已经完成了。而
you've got something like a whole grain
像全谷物
or a nut typically that would be
或坚果之类的食物，通常会在消化道
absorbed lower down the gastrointestinal
下部被吸收，
stress tra where you got more of these
那里有更多的
fullness signals so giving you that
饱腹信号，因此会让你产生
greater feeling of fullness my
更强烈的饱腹感。我的
girlfriend has said to me for many many
女朋友多年来一直跟我说
a year that I need to eat slower Y and I
我需要吃慢点，我
thought it was like a spiritual thing
以前以为这是
that she's into um to do with like
她信奉的一种精神层面的东西，比如对
giving the food gratitude etc etc but
食物心存感激等等。 等等，但是
upon reading your work and having this
读了你的作品，又和你
conversation today now I'm starting to
今天聊了聊之后，我开始
believe that she was right all along
相信她一直都是对的，这并不
unsurprisingly once again um and that
奇怪，而且
slowing down how fast I eat absolutely
放慢进食速度确实有科学依据。
we now know that eating rate is
我们现在知道进食速度很
important there's some fantastic work
重要，基伦·福特教授在这方面做了一些非常棒的研究，
Ford who's dedicated many years into
他多年来致力于
researching this and looking at how
研究食物的
changing the structure and texture of
结构和质地如何
your food can modulate your eating rate
调节进食速度，
and how also your eating rate can
以及进食速度如何
modulate um how you metabolize the food
调节食物代谢
and how many calories you go on to eat
和摄入的卡路里数量。
and so it's a great example you know I
这是一个很好的例子，你知道，我之前提到过很多
talked about all of these different
不同的
pieces of the puzzle that's one of those
因素，这只是其中之一。
pieces so when we talk about how you eat
当我们谈到饮食时，
changing your eating rate so how quickly
改变进食速度，也就是
you have your breakfast your lunch or
你吃早餐、午餐、
dinner or any of these snacks will also
晚餐或任何零食的速度，会在
Without You consciously thinking about
你不知不觉中
it change how many calories you eat
改变你摄入的卡路里数量，也
might change how quickly you metabolize
可能改变你代谢
the food as well what's the sort of
食物的速度。那么，这会产生哪些
KnockOn effects there so the research
连锁反应呢？
that's been done by Ken Ford shows that
基伦·福特的研究表明，
on average if you change the speed in
平均而言，如果你 改变
which you eat your food by about
进食速度约
20% you reduce your calories intake by
20%，就能减少
about
约
15% and that's due to where you're
15%的卡路里摄入。这是因为进食速度会影响
releasing your hunger hormones how many
饥饿激素和
fullness hormones you're releasing Etc
饱腹激素的分泌量等等。
so it's a really simple strategy and we
这是一个非常简单的策略，我们也从
own evidence when we look in our zor
自身的研究中看到了这一点。当我们比较
predict studies that fast eaters versus
快食者和
slow eaters we see that once we're just
慢食者时，我们发现，在排除
for lots of other confounders there's a
其他混杂因素后，快食者和
fast eaters have over a day versus slow
慢食者一天摄入的卡路里相差120卡路里，
eaters with the fast eaters eating more
快食者比慢食者摄入更多。
there's even been clinical trials where
甚至还有一些临床试验，研究人员将
they get groups of individuals and say
受试者分成几组，让他们在
your food over the next you know three
接下来的三到
four five weeks they have another group
五周内放慢进食速度，另一组则保持正常进食速度。结果发现，那些
those people who are intentionally
刻意
slowing down the rate at which they eat
放慢进食速度的人
their food lose more weight than those
比那些
people who continue to eat at their
保持正常进食
rate see I always made this like weird
速度的人减重更多。你看，我总是
unfounded evolutionary argument to her I
跟她说一些奇怪又毫无根据的进化论论点，比如，
was like well you know in the wild you
你知道， 在野外，
got to eat what you can so people eat
人们只能吃能找到的食物，所以他们吃得
quick but um we're not in the world
很快。但是，我们现在所处的环境已经截然不同，
anymore and the food choices that we
食物选择也发生了
have are drastically different now so
翻天覆地的变化。
yeah and also the food that is available
而且，我们很多人能吃到的食物都是那种可以
can be eaten really quickly so there's
快速食用的食物。
some great research that's been
一些研究表明，
conducted that shows that heavily
高度
processed soft textured type food can be
加工的软质食物
eaten 50% more quickly than the
比未经加工的硬质食物的食用速度快50%。
so the kind of food that we're eating
所以，我们现在吃的食物类型已经
now is quite different so you're eating
大相径庭。你吃得
it really quickly you're overeating
很快，但
because your hunger signals haven't got
因为饥饿信号还没来得及
there but it's that rate at which you're
出现，所以很容易吃过量。那么，
eating what's an example of a soft
软
textured food versus like a hard
质食物和硬
textured
质
food so we can use an example from a
食物有什么区别呢？我们可以举一个
1977 and this was published in the Lan
1977年进行的研究的例子，这项研究发表在《营养学杂志》（LAN）上，
it was one of the first nutrition
是最早
studies published um in the lanet and
发表在LAN上的营养学研究之一，也是
it's one of the first studies to show
最早揭示
the importance of the food Matrix and it
食物矩阵重要性的研究之一。
this a study by uh the scientist called
这项研究多年来一直被埋没。 一位名叫哈伯的科学家做了一个实验，
habber where he fed individuals whole
他让受试者分别食用完整的
apples MH he fed individuals the
苹果和等量的苹果
Apple puree it was exactly the same I.E
泥。苹果泥和苹果的碳水化合物含量完全相同，
same nutrients same fiber same
营养成分、纤维含量和
everything else in it all that's
其他所有成分都一样。唯一的
different is the apples are hard the
区别是苹果比较硬，
puree is soft and what he found was that
而苹果泥比较软。哈伯发现，
even though they were given exactly the
即使摄入的
same amount of calories ate that puree
卡路里总量相同，食用苹果泥的人吃苹果泥的速度（
or rather drank that puree three to four
或者说喝苹果泥的速度）也比食用等量苹果的人快三到四倍，也就是
times more quickly that's like 300% 400%
快了3到4倍。而且，食用苹果泥的人饱腹
faster okay they felt less full so when
感更弱。研究人员
they measured their fullness and they
测量了他们的饱腹感，并持续
monitored that for quite a few hours so
监测了几个小时。结果发现，
were having the apples continued to feel
食用苹果的人饱腹感持续时间
full for longer those were having the
更长，而食用苹果
puree didn't feel full as long
泥的人饱腹感持续时间更短。
and what also happened interestingly is
更有趣的是，食用苹果泥的
those that were having the puree had
人在
2 to four hours after having a high
摄入高碳水化合物食物后2到4小时会出现血糖下降。
carbohydrate meal we know that some
我们知道，有些
people have a dip in their circulating
人在摄入高碳水化合物食物后会出现血糖下降。 循环
blood sugar and we know from our own zo
血糖，我们从自己的Zo-
predict research that actually this can
Predict研究中得知，这实际上会显著
really increase your hunger levels yeah
增加你的饥饿感。是的，
and so we know from our research if you
我们的研究表明，如果你
are a Dipper I'm a Dipper hence I get
是“昼夜节律型”（Dipper，指血糖波动较大的食物类型），比如我，我
hungry quite often so in about two hours
经常感到饥饿。大约两个小时后，
I'm going to be eating one of these if
我就会吃点东西。如果
you're a Dipper you know your your blood
你是“昼夜节律型”食物，你的
gluc is going below your Baseline levels
血糖会低于基础水平，
and so you get hungry you go on to eat
因此你会感到饥饿，并
180 calories on average more at your
在下一餐平均多摄入180卡路里。
next meal because of that and so I mean
所以，
this research from 1977 I think is
我认为这项1977年的研究非常
fascinating it's that first research
引人入胜，它是第一个
really demonstrating the importance of
真正证明
food Matrix and then since then I've now
食物矩阵重要性的研究。从那以后，在
over the last 10 years done lots of
过去的十年里，我做了很多关于
studies with nuts with oats for example
坚果和燕麦的研究，这些研究
that demonstrate you can have two foods
表明，两种食物可能拥有
that have identical backpack labeling
相同的
identical nutrients ident identical
营养成分表，相同的
calorie value if you were to look at the
卡路里值。如果你查看它们的
back of Lo but can have entirely
背面，你会发现它们实际上含有相同的营养成分。 虽然
energy you absorb how you metabolize
它们对能量的吸收、
that food how it impacts your hunger how
食物代谢、饥饿感
it impacts Downstream health effects and
以及后续健康影响都可能完全不同，但
you've done some research on walnuts
你对核桃做过一些研究，对吧？我们
right so we've done work on walnuts but
确实研究过核桃，但
particularly on almonds so we've done
尤其研究过杏仁。我们
lots of work with almonds using it as a
用杏仁做了很多研究，将其作为
importance of the food Matrix now you
食物基质重要性的证明和原理。你
just took a bite of that and I could
刚才咬了一口，我能
hear the crunch the reason I could hear
听到嘎吱声。我能听到嘎吱声的原因是，
the crunches cuz in almonds like most
杏仁和大多数
nuts like many plant-based projects uh
坚果、许多植物性产品一样，
products um there is a very um rigid
都有非常坚硬的
cell wall okay so that almond that you
细胞壁。你手里
you're holding there has thousands and
拿着的这颗杏仁里有
thousands and thousands of cells these
成千上万个细胞，这些
cells are tiny they're about 50 microns
细胞非常小，大约只有50微米。
okay you can't see them with the human
肉眼无法看到它们，
eye I can show you a micrograph okay um
我可以给你看一张显微照片。
but there's thousands in there now each
里面有成千上万个
of those cells is smaller than a grain
细胞，每个细胞都比一粒
of sand and each of those cells is
沙子还小，而且每个细胞都被
encapsulate cell walls is encapsulating
细胞壁包裹着。 脂肪被包裹在坚硬的细胞壁中，
the fat so we know that in most of these
所以我们知道大多数
nuts it's about 50% they're about 50%
坚果的脂肪含量约为50%。
fat hence people say my gosh I can't eat
因此人们会说：“天哪，我不能吃
nuts they're high fat they're high
坚果，它们脂肪含量高，
calorie now in all of those nuts the
热量也高。”所有这些坚果中的
fats encapsulated in this rigid cell
脂肪都被包裹在坚硬的
wall when you bit that you fractured
细胞壁中。当你咬坚果时，你会破坏
some of
一些
those cell walls when you swallow it you
细胞壁。当你吞咽坚果时，你会
chewed it you chewed it a little bit I
咀嚼它，你会稍微咀嚼一下。我
assume a little bit yeah yeah I didn't
猜是的，我并没有完全
swallow it
吞咽。
when people chew it we know from these
我们从
lovely chew and spit studies or
咀嚼和吐出研究或
mastication studies that we do that at
咀嚼研究中得知，当
the point at which you swallow a knut
你吞咽坚果时，你吞咽的、
you've chewed are about maybe half a
咀嚼过的颗粒大小约为0.5
millim to 1 mm in size now given that
毫米到1毫米。考虑到
the cell within or of a alut is about 50
坚果内部的细胞厚度约为50
microns that means when you're
微米，这意味着当你
swallowing within that what we call a
吞咽我们称之为
macro particle you got thousands of
大颗粒的物质时，其中包含数千个
cells they're intact where you've got
完整的细胞，这些细胞被包裹在
this lovely cell wall containing all of
坚硬的细胞壁中，而细胞壁又包含所有
this fat and so you're swallowing these
这些脂肪。 你吞下的是这些
intact cells containing encapsulating
完整的细胞，它们包裹着
the fat so they're what we call very low
脂肪，所以我们称之为“低可及性”脂肪，
by accessibility they're not very
我们很难
accessible to us this
吸收利用。当这些
fat now what happens as this passes
脂肪
through your gastrointestinal tract some
通过你的消化道时会发生什么呢？一些
of the enzymes can break down the cells
酶可以稍微分解这些细胞，
a little bit but actually a lot just
但实际上大部分脂肪会从
comes out the other end so I don't know
另一端排出。我不知道
whether you've ever eaten a bag of nuts
你有没有吃过一袋坚果，然后拉出来——这跟
and to your poo after none of your
你没关系，
business I'm joking okay go and do
我开玩笑的。好吧，你可以试试。
that but you should
你应该能
see some Alma particles you know like
看到一些坚果颗粒。你知道，就像
when I'm you know being a mom when I've
我当妈妈的时候，我这辈子因为
through my work but also through being a
工作和当妈妈观察过很多粪便，
mom you can see whole nut particles in
你会发现粪便里有完整的坚果颗粒。
the Poo so nuts they just is it they
坚果就是这样，它们
just don't break down fully so they
不能完全分解，只能
break down partially so you break down
部分分解。
10% in the mouth before you swallow so
在你吞咽之前，大约有10%的坚果在口腔中被分解，所以大约
about 10% of the calories become
10%的卡路里可以被
available because the calories are
利用，因为卡路里
contained from the fat
来自脂肪
Etc and then you probably break down
等等。然后，
about another 60 to 70% as it passes
当它们
through your stomach your small
通过你的胃时，可能还有60%到70%的坚果会被分解。 你的
intestine your large intestine okay but
小肠和大肠都消化了，但
you have loads of material arriving at
有很多未消化的物质会到达
your colon which is your large intestine
你的结肠，也就是你的大肠。
that's undigested which is good for two
这有两个
reasons one because you're giving all of
好处：一是
this food to your microbiome which we
这些食物会提供给你的肠道菌群，我们
know is great for your health your
知道这对你的健康非常有益；你的
microbiome is having a party with these
肠道菌群正在享用这些
nuts
坚果；
but also if you are worried about eating
二是如果你担心
nuts because of their high calorie value
坚果热量高，
actually 20 to 30% of the calories are
实际上有20%到30%的热量会通过肠道排出
just coming out the other end but where
体外。但
it gets really interesting is if we then
真正有趣的是，如果我们把
take exactly that nut that you're
你手里拿着的这颗坚果进行
industrially grind it so that I broke
工业研磨，破坏
all of those cells walls yeah so we're
所有的细胞壁，把
breaking it down to less than 50 microns
它研磨到小于50微米，
so that you're releasing all of the fat
这样就能释放出所有的脂肪，使其
so it becomes 100% bi accessible either
100%被人体吸收。也就是说，
you absorb 100% % of it but they could
你可以100%吸收它。但它们的
have two identical back aack labels yeah
背面标签可能完全相同，
because if they're the same ingredient
因为如果它们是同一种成分，那么发生的一切
all that's happened is you've ground
只是你把
that nut to such an extent that you've
坚果研磨到一定程度，
released
释放出了
everything and so having that in its
所有成分。 它的
whole form is beneficial because if you
完整形态是有益的，因为如果你
are concerned about energy intake it's
担心能量摄入，它会
reducing the energy it's providing this
减少能量消耗，
amazing food for your G microbiome it's
为你的肠道菌群提供绝佳的食物，还会
changing also how you your blood changes
改变你血液的代谢方式。
metabolically in that about 8 hours
大约在
after eating it and this is what I've
食用后8小时内，这种改变尤为明显。我
done lots of work on looking at how your
做了很多研究，观察
that immediate period after eating
食用磨碎的坚果
either ground nuts or whole nuts but
或完整的坚果后，血液脂肪在短时间内的变化。但
once you grind it I'm not saying it's
磨碎坚果并不意味着它
necessarily bad because the upside of
一定不好，因为好处
that is all of the other good nutrients
是，细胞中包含的其他有益营养物质，
contained within that cell like the
例如
vitamin E and some of the other
维生素E和其他一些
components also become available so it's
成分，也能被人体吸收利用。所以，它是一把
this double-edged sword interesting but
双刃剑，很有意思。但
that's what I think is so fascinating
我认为，食物
about processing and about food Matrix
加工和食物基质的魅力就在于此，
and why we have to move Beyond thinking
也正是我们需要超越仅仅从
nutrients because you can have two foods
营养成分的角度来思考食物的原因。因为两种食物即使
with identical backpack labeling that
包装标签完全相同，也可能产生
have different effects and we've seen
不同的效果。我们在
the same with oats we've been doing
燕麦上也看到了同样的现象。我们做过一些
studies as well where we feed people um
研究，给人们喂食
large oats so kind of you know like the
大块燕麦，就像那种老式的燕麦粥一样。
and so we've done clinical trials where
我们进行了临床试验，
on one occasion people come in and
受试者
they'll have 50 gr carbohydrate for
先吃50克碳水化合物的
breakfast of these large oats then
大燕麦片作为早餐，
they'll come in another day and they'll
第二天再吃
have exactly the same oats but where we
同样的燕麦片，但这次我们把燕麦磨碎了。
ground them literally we've got students
我们让学生把
just grinding them down so they're more
燕麦磨成粉末状。结果发现，
hours after having either the large
食用大
traditional oats or these finy ground
燕麦片和磨碎的
oats is enormous and that's because of
燕麦片六小时后，受试者的代谢反应差异巨大。这是因为
gut absorption speed yes so with the
肠道吸收速度不同。坚果的吸收速度和吸收量都
is a difference in the amount as well as
不同，而
the speed with the oats what we're
燕麦的吸收
seeing is a difference in the speed so
速度不同。
rate because we know that the food
我们知道食物
Matrix impacts the amount I with the
基质会影响吸收量（
nuts the rate are with the oats and as
坚果）和吸收率（燕麦），
well as where the foods absorbed in the
以及食物在肠道中的吸收位置。
gut and so you see about a 40%
因此，
blood glucose after you've had these
食用
oats we see about a 50% higher response
燕麦后，血糖反应（即循环血糖升高）的差异约为40%。 与燕麦片相比，燕麦粉的反应高出50%，
and that has subsequent impacts on
这会对
hunger hormones fullness hormones
饥饿激素、饱腹激素、
insulin release etc etc and what role
胰岛素释放等产生后续影响。
does fiber play in this because fiber is
纤维在其中扮演什么角色呢？因为纤维
becoming quite popular now they're like
现在非常流行，人们把
putting it in drinks and stuff like that
它添加到饮料之类的东西里。
and I I there was some candy in America
我在美国纽约录音的时候，看到一种糖果，上面写着
grams of fiber added to this like
添加了15克纤维。
candy so fiber is a really interesting
所以纤维真的很有意思，
because we know we're not getting enough
因为我们知道我们摄入的
fiber M so we should be getting at least
纤维不足。在英国，我们应该至少摄入
30 grams of fiber in the UK and it's
30克纤维，
similar in the US we get on average
美国的情况也类似，我们平均摄入
about 20 grams of fiber 95% of us are
约20克纤维。95%的人
not having enough fiber fiber is the one
纤维摄入不足。纤维是已知
associated with beneficial health
与多种健康
effects reduce reduction in many cancers
益处密切相关的营养素，它可以降低多种癌症、
reduction in cardiovascular disease
心血管疾病、
reduction in levels of obesity type 2
肥胖症和2型
diabetes Etc you know it's an amazing
糖尿病的风险。你知道，纤维是一种神奇的
nutrient fiber and we don't get enough
营养素，但我们摄入的纤维却不足。
of it just to pause there then why is it
停顿一下，为什么它对
so good for us because I mean it sounds
我们这么好呢？我的意思是…… 听起来
like a super molecule the way you just
就像你刚才描述的那种超级分子，
described it so it's good for us for
它对我们有很多好处。
and loads of different types of fiber
纤维有很多种，每种
and the different types of fiber are
纤维对
good for us for slightly different
我们有益的原因略有不同。
reasons really simply put we've got
简单来说，我们有
soluble fiber and that's great for us
可溶性纤维，它对我们很好，
because it impacts things like
因为它会影响
cholesterol absorption as well as other
胆固醇的吸收以及其他与
factors related to how quickly we
我们食物代谢速度相关的因素
metabolize food Etc then you've got uh
等等。还有不溶性纤维，比如坚果里就含有这种纤维，
because fiber in those nuts is actually
因为坚果里的纤维实际上是
the cell wall so most cell walls of
细胞壁。大多数植物的细胞壁都是
plants are just fiber that's great for
纤维，它对
us because it's fued for our microbiome
我们很好，因为它能为我们的肠道菌群提供食物，
it helps bulk out our store so reduces
帮助增加粪便体积，缩短粪便通过
basically passes to our colon reduce the
肠道的时间，降低
risk of colon cancer and so forth but
结肠癌的风险等等。但
largely because it is the food upon
最主要的是，它是
which our microbiom have their party
我们肠道菌群
produce all of these wonderful molecules
产生各种有益分子的食物，这些分子
that we no impact so much related to our
对我们的健康影响很大。
health but we don't get enough of it and
但我们摄入的纤维不够，
we don't get enough of it because we're
因为我们
not eating the right types of food that
没有吃对纤维的种类。
we have in high amounts so having any
我们摄入的食物中纤维含量很高，所以摄入任何
kind of fiber is going to improve our
类型的纤维都会改善我们的
health having fiber that's added
健康。人工添加的纤维也比完全
be better than having no fiber so the
不摄入纤维要好。
kind of bars that you're talking about
你提到的那些标榜
that say are added fiber great having
添加了纤维的能量棒固然不错，
fiber though from the whole food is
但从天然食物中摄取纤维
always going to be better and so with
总是更好的选择。坚果中的
nuts fiber is essentially the the cell
纤维本质上是
walls of the nuts so it's having that
坚果的细胞壁，它会
role in reducing that bio accessibility
降低我们之前提到的生物利用度，也就是减缓坚果的吸收速度。
down so that's always going to be better
因此，
having that fiber in the whole food in
以天然食物的
its original structure in the way nature
原始结构摄取纤维总是更好的选择。
intended but having any kind of fiber is
但无论如何，摄入任何类型的纤维都比完全
better than having none and in a nation
不摄入纤维要好。在一些国家，或者
or or you know many nations where we're
说很多国家，我们摄入的纤维
not having enough if we can get some in
不足，如果我们能在饮食中摄入一些纤维，
our diet even if it is processed fiber
即使是加工纤维，也比完全不摄入
it's better than fiber in my opinion one
纤维要好。在我看来，
of the um big revelations in my
我家最近的一个重大改变就是把
household has been just getting some of
一些
these bad snacks just out the house and
不健康的零食扔掉，
replacing it with um healthier whole
换成更健康的天然
snacks and I say that because the sort
零食。我说这话是因为
sort of use case where we snack is when
我们吃零食的典型情况就是，
we typically don't have a lot of time
我们通常不会吃零食。 很多时候，
where hunger kind of crept up on us in
饥饿感会在
between a meal um and so we make fast
两餐之间悄悄袭来，所以我们会迅速做出
decisions it's not a very considered
决定，而不是深思熟虑。
decision um and I was reading
我读到
that there's been some studies done
一些研究，
where they took sort of two groups and
他们把受试者分成两组，一组吃
gave them typical snacks versus healthy
普通零食，另一组吃健康零食，结果
snacks and they found a pretty
发现健康零食组的
significant reduction in cardiovascular
心血管
disease yeah so this is one of my
疾病发病率显著降低。是的，这是我的
studies okay um and we looked at how
研究之一。我们研究了
changing people's snacks can impact
改变人们的零食习惯如何影响
their health and the reason we're
他们的健康。我们之所以
interested in this is because we're a
对此感兴趣，是因为
nation of snackers in the UK as in many
英国和许多其他国家一样，都是一个爱吃零食的民族。
countries so we know that about 25% of
我们知道，大约25%的
our energy comes from snacks that's
能量来自零食，这真是
phenomenal and so what we wanted to do
惊人。所以我们想
is look at if we do a really simple
看看，如果我们进行一个非常简单的
snack
零食
swap can we improve People's Health and
替换，能否改善人们的健康。
so we ask people to change 20% of their
我们要求参与者在六周内，将20%的
energy from either having typical UK
能量摄入
from alond nuts for 6 weeks and then we
从普通英国零食（例如马铃薯、马铃薯、马铃薯和坚果）转移到其他食物。然后，
the end of that six weeks we said keep
我们在六周开始时和结束时观察了各种健康指标。
everything else the same we provided all
我们给
of these snacks to them we provided the
他们提供了所有这些零食，都是
typical UK snacks we spent a lot of time
典型的英国零食。我们花了很多时间
designing these so we did lots of
设计这些零食，做了很多
research where we looked in the UK and
研究。我们考察了英国和
it's the very similar in the US what are
美国，发现它们非常相似，所以研究了
the typical snacks so basically we
典型的英国零食是什么。基本上，我们
designed these muffins that ultimately
设计了这些松饼，最终的成品就像把
were having a bit of a potato chip or
薯片、巧克力饼干和蛋糕都
of a cake just like imagine all put in
放进
one muffin I mean we didn't go and get
一个松饼里一样。我的意思是，我们并没有真的把
those and just stick them in one muffin
这些东西都放进去，而是
but we worked out what's the nutrient
研究了
profile in the UK in the us that comes
英国和美国
from snacks and then we designed a snack
零食的营养成分，然后设计了一种
product that was quite highly processed
高度加工的零食产品，以
that reflected that nutrient profile so
反映这些营养成分。这种零食
it's quite high in saturated fat high in
饱和脂肪、
sugar high in refined carbohydrate low
糖和精制碳水化合物含量很高，
in fiber people had to eat 20% of their
纤维含量很低。人们必须
energy from these muffins which my kids
从这些松饼（我的孩子们
loved um or 20% from the almond nuts at
很喜欢）或杏仁中摄取20%的能量。
the end of that we measured lots of
最后，我们测量了很多
health outcomes one of which was a
健康指标，其中一项是
particular measure that we do to look at
专门用来测量
people's vascular function so their
人们血管功能的指标。
blood vessel function it's a measure
一项
called flow Medi dilation it tells us in
名为血流介导扩张的指标，可以用
really simple terms kind of how healthy
非常简单的方式告诉我们
the blood vessels are and what we found
血管的健康状况。我们发现，与食用
versus having typical UK snacks equated
典型的英国零食相比，食用杏仁后血管功能的改善相当于
to a 30% reduction in cardiovascular
心血管疾病风险降低了30%，这太
disease that's crazy and in what period
不可思议了！而且，这种效果只用了
of time six weeks in six weeks and do
六周时间。
you know what I think's
你知道吗，我认为这项研究
really interesting about this is it's
真正有趣的地方在于，它仅仅是
one simple single dietary strategy
一种简单的饮食策略，
and snacks are under our own control
而且零食的选择完全由我们自己掌控。
typically I what I have as a snack isn't
通常情况下，我吃什么零食不会受到
determined by my fussy kids what high
挑食的孩子的影响，也
have as a snack quite often isn't
不会受到
determined where I am at that point in
我当时所处环境的限制，
time because I can bring my snacks with
因为我可以随身携带零食。
me it's a really simple single diet
这是一种非常简单的饮食
strategy that can have a big size effect
策略，却能产生如此巨大的影响，
and I think that that's really important
我认为这非常
it is really important though Stephen at
重要。不过，斯蒂芬，
this point that I do say that I have
我必须说明，
of California and they did fund uh that
这项研究实际上得到了加州阿尔玛委员会的资助。
study although the way we conduct our
尽管如此，在我们进行随机对照试验的过程中，
RCT the funders have no impact over the
资助方不会干预
study design or you know they don't get
研究设计，他们也无法
to see the all data or or the paper
看到所有数据。 在
before we're publishing it but I just
我们发表这篇论文之前，我
think it's always important to declare
认为声明利益冲突始终很重要。
interest we've seen this though play out
我们
in other studies with other nuts or
在其他关于其他坚果或其他
other snack substitutes so it's not
零食替代品的研究中也看到了这种情况，所以这并非
unique just to almonds it's a great
杏仁独有。这很好地
illustrator of how changing our snacks
说明了改变零食习惯
can improve our health and we we really
如何改善我们的健康。我们真是
are a nation of snackers um you
一个爱吃零食的民族。你刚才
highlighted one of the stats there that
提到的一个数据是，
in the UK and in the US about 25% of our
在英国和美国，大约25%的
energy comes from snacks 75% of the
能量来自零食，而这些零食中75%的
energy that's coming from those snacks
能量
is coming from unhealthy snacks this was
来自不健康零食。这个数据
taken from The Zo podcast uh in
来自Zo播客。
mediteran in Mediterranean countries
在地中海国家，
only 14% of energy comes from snacks
只有14%的能量来自零食，这相当于
which is half of the UK and 85% of
英国的一半。85%的
British people report snacking compared
英国人表示会吃零食，而
to 10% in France and in the UK we have
法国只有10%。在英国，我们平均
2.5 to three snacks per day which
每天吃2.5到3次零食，
translates to six or seven eating events
相当于每天6到7次进食。
a day um and this has massive impact and
这会造成巨大的影响，导致
our glucose spikes and drops throughout
我们的血糖在
the day causing metabolic chaos and
一天中剧烈波动，造成代谢紊乱。
that's part of what I was thinking as I
这也是我之前提到的部分原因。 我刚才在想，
if I'm eating that muffin that you made
如果我吃了你做的那个松饼，它有点像
which resembles the sort of typical
典型的
British composition of a snack it's not
英式零食，那么
going to impact me it's that my next
影响我的不仅仅是这个零食本身，而是
Food choice because I ate that snack is
因为我吃了它，我接下来的食物选择也会有所
going to be different because I'm on
不同。因为我的血糖
that I might be on a glucose roller
可能会像坐过山车一样波动，
coaster here so I might end up making a
所以我之后可能会选择
worse food Choice thereafter which then
更糟糕的食物，这反过来
might impact my maybe my sleep because
又会影响我的睡眠，因为
when I'm settling down to go to sleep
我在准备睡觉的时候体内还有一些糖分。这是否会产生一种连锁反应，就像多米诺骨牌
and is there the sort of not Downstream
一样？
choice so I wouldn't say that you've
所以，我不会说你
made a one bad snack choice and that's
选错了一次零食，然后你的
it your day's over damn it you know
一天就结束了，该死的，你吃撑了。不过，
you're stuffed I think that you
我认为你
highlight an important point though that
强调了一个重要的观点，那就是
what we choose as a meal does have knock
我们选择的餐食确实会对一天中
on effects on what might happen later in
晚些时候发生的事情产生连锁反应。
the day so for example if you have a
例如，如果你
really refined carbohydrate breakfast or
早餐或零食吃的是精制碳水化合物，
snack then you're more likely to have a
那么你的血糖就更容易
blood sugar dip which we know from our
下降，我们从
research is more likely to make you um
研究中得知…… 零食更容易让你感到
more hungry eat more calories have lower
饥饿，摄入更多卡路里，导致
mood have lower energy and be less alert
情绪低落、精力不足和注意力不集中。
but I think you know
但我认为，
snacking can be used to our advantage
零食也可以被
because we know it accounts for such a
因为它占
huge proportion of our energy intake
我们能量摄入的很大一部分。
because we know on average that you know
我们知道，
70 75% snacks that we do come eat in the
在英国和美国，我们平均吃的零食中有70%到75%
UK and the US are not helpful snacks and
都是不健康的。
because we know that actually just
我们也知道，
transitioning from those to healthy
从这些不健康的零食过渡到健康的
snacks can have a big impact but I think
零食可以产生很大的影响。但我认为，
about not just the type of snacks you're
不仅要考虑零食的种类，
having but the time of day that you're
还要考虑
having the snacks and we published some
吃零食的时间，这一点非常重要。我们最近发表了一项
research recently where we looked in a
研究，调查了
thousand individuals at people's
一千个人的
snacking habits because it's not
零食习惯，因为这方面的研究并不
actually been looked at much I mean you
多。我的意思是，你可能会
think everyone snacks you think there'd
认为每个人都会吃零食，你可能会认为应该有
be loads of science out there about
很多关于
snacking there's lots of science out
零食的科学研究。有很多科学研究是关于
that we might snack on but not really
我们可能吃的各种零食，但很少有研究关注
much looking at snacking habits and
零食习惯。
about whether we should be grazers and
关于我们是否应该吃零食，目前存在很多争议。 我们都是爱吃零食的人，
we are a nation of grazers you know we
你知道，我们是一个爱吃零食的民族。
well I certainly graze but many people
我当然也吃零食，但
we know like you said you know 80 to 90%
就像你说的，我们认识的很多
of people do have multiple eating events
人
throughout the day are you taking these
一天都会吃好几顿。你是为了
away from you for self-control I am a
自控力才限制自己吃零食的吗？我
little bit Yeah I think uh the the smell
有点儿。嗯，我觉得
of the chocolate and the cookies is
巧克力和饼干的香味在
testing me and in Janu I'm not trying to
考验我，一月份我可不想
be tested there we go um
被考验。好了，
and what we have never really fully
我们一直没能完全
understood is is snacking per se bad are
弄明白的是，吃零食本身到底好不好？是指一天吃
you having multiple eating events so
好几顿，比如像
do in the UK and the
英国和
us or is it about the type of food we're
美国那样一天吃六顿吗？还是说关键在于零食的种类？
snacking on so should we revert back to
我们应该恢复一日
having the three main meals the
三餐（
breakfast the lunch the dinner or is it
早餐、午餐、晚餐）吗？还是
okay to have multiple meals as long as
只要吃的是
it's healthy food so we looked at this
健康食品，吃多顿也无妨？我们
in our cohort of a thousand individuals
在一项针对一千人的研究中对此进行了调查，
where we taken lots of measures related
我们测量了
to what they're eating when they're
他们吃什么、什么时候
eating how they're eating it as well as
吃、怎么吃，以及
lots of different Health outcomes and
各种不同的健康指标。
what we found was that the frequency of
我们发现，
eating within reason was not a problem
在合理的范围内进食频率是有益的。
so if people were grazing having
所以，如果人们吃零食，也就是一天吃
multiple eating events as long as they
多顿饭，只要
were eating healthy foods it didn't
吃的是健康食物，
matter having multiple eating events so
那么吃
snacking per se wasn't a problem as long
零食本身并不是问题。因为关于一天应该吃几顿饭，一直以来都存在着
I guess raging debate about how many
激烈的争论。
meals you should have a day some people
有些人一天
just eat one meal a day some people
只吃一顿饭，有些人
probably five or six meals a day and
一天可能吃五六顿。
you're saying it doesn't necessarily
你的意思是，
matter as long as what you're eating is
只要吃的是
healthy yeah I mean I will always as a
健康食物，吃几顿饭就不一定重要？是的，作为一名谨慎的科学家，我总是会在合理的范围内给出答案。
but our research showed people having
但我们的研究表明，人们
six eating events a day I you know six
一天吃六顿饭（也就是六次
different occasions that they're eating
不同的进食机会）
food or three eating events as long as
或者吃三顿饭，只要
they were eating or snacking on healthy
吃的是健康
foods it did not impact their health
食物，都不会影响他们的健康
outcome
状况。而且，
and this is I guess controlled for
这项研究已经排除了
extreme cases where someone's maybe
极端情况，比如有人
eating at 1:00 a.m. in the morning or 2:
凌晨1点或2点吃东西。
a.m. in the morning yeah so we also
所以我们也
looked at timing because I think that's
研究了进食时间，因为我认为
attention to in nutrition science and
营养科学领域对进食时间的关注还不够，而
it's a really exciting new area of
这确实是一个非常令人兴奋的新领域。
research that we're starting to
我们开始
understand the timing of when we eat is
了解进食时间的重要性，这项研究
really important and what we found was
非常有趣。我们发现，
interestingly 30% of people were
30%的人在
night and we found that if you snack
晚上9点后吃零食。我们发现，如果你在深夜吃零食，你会
late at night I feel
感到
attacked and this is a l in line with
不适。这与
you know other published research from
其他已发表的、来自
very tightly controlled clinical trials
严格控制的临床试验的研究结果一致。这些研究
we found that if you snack late at night
发现，如果你在深夜吃零食，会导致
unfavorable Health outcomes so uh worse
不良的健康结果，
belly for example um higher levels of
例如腹部脂肪堆积、
inflammation worse levels of blood lipid
炎症水平升高、血脂水平升高（例如
so you know cholesterol that sort of
胆固醇升高）等等。
thing and we found that this was even if
我们发现，即使
you were snacking on healthy snacks
你吃的是健康零食，也会出现这种情况。
really and this isn't especially
这并不特别令人
surprising because there's this whole
惊讶，因为
new area in nutrition called chronon
营养学中有一个全新的领域叫做时间
nutrition which is all about the timing
营养学，它关注的是
of eating and we now are really starting
进食时间。我们现在开始真正
to understand that every cell in our
理解，我们身体的每个细胞
body has its little body clock has a
都有自己的生物钟，每个
clock every cell has a clock and that
细胞都有一个生物钟，这个
clock is shaped by when we eat as well
生物钟会受到我们进食时间和
as the light day cycle and if we're
昼夜循环的影响。如果我们不按时进食，就会扰乱
in our body we know that we process the
我们体内数以亿计的生物钟。 我们对
food slightly differently we metabolize
食物的处理和代谢方式略有不同，
it slightly differently and it may have
这可能会对
a different impact on our health and
我们的健康产生不同的影响，
that's what our research showed as well
我们的研究也证实了这一点。因此，
9:00 isn't great for your health just a
晚上9点以后进食对健康不利，而且只会增加
double down on that I have had a
双倍的摄入量。 关于这一点，我一直以来都有一个
hypothesis that when I eat later at
假设：如果我晚上吃得太晚，
increasing my belly fat now I I don't
我的腹部脂肪就会增加。虽然我
have any science to support this but
没有科学依据来支持这个假设，但确实存在这种感觉。而且，
when I wake up is radically different if
如果
I've eaten close to my sleep time so I
我在睡前吃东西，醒来后的感觉也会截然不同。所以我
had this weird hypothesis that I'm
有一个很奇怪的假设：我就像
basically putting food into the machine
把食物放进机器里，
and then I'm like turning the machine
然后在
off while it's processing so it's kind
它还在处理的时候就把它关掉了，所以它
of like not processed it properly yeah I
没有被完全处理掉。嗯，
mean that's kind of a simple terms
简单来说，就是我们
our body needs to rest overnight just
身体需要休息，就像
like our mind does ourselves our
我们的大脑需要休息一样，我们的
metabolism needs to rest overnight and
新陈代谢也需要休息。
if you're not giving your body your
如果你不给你的身体——你的
cells your metabolism your got
细胞、你的新陈代谢、你的
microbiome Etc that time to rest things
微生物群等等——足够的休息时间，这些都会受到
get Disturbed a little bit and what's
一些干扰。
really interesting is you said that
真正有趣的是，你说
you'll feel different the next day if
如果
you eat late at night there's some
你晚上吃得太晚，第二天会感觉不一样。大约一两年前，有一些非常
really fascinating research that came
有趣的研究发表，
they looked at giving exactly the same
他们研究了在一天中摄入相同
calories and Foods over the day within
卡路里和食物的情况。
the same time period but on in one group
但是，一组
of individuals having most of the
人大部分
calories earlier and in another group
卡路里摄入时间较早，另一组人
having most of them later in the day now
大部分​​卡路里摄入时间较晚。结果发现，
those that were having them later in the
那些在一天中较晚摄入卡路里的人
day woke up feeling more hungry which is
醒来后感觉更饿，这
kind of like counterintuitive isn't it
似乎有点违反直觉，不是吗？但这
but it fits in with what you just said
与你刚才说的吻合。而
yet those people who are eating the
那些在一天中较早摄入卡路里的人
day woke up feeling less hungry and this
醒来后感觉没那么饿。这也是
is why as well the evidence shows early
为什么有证据表明，在一天中较早进行
Tim restricted eating so time restricted
限时饮食（即在
particular time window those people who
特定时间段内进食）的人，
to do better in terms of the health
在健康方面往往表现更好，
outcomes whether it's weight
无论是在体重、
inflammation cholesterol than those
炎症还是胆固醇方面，都优于那些在一天中
practicing later time restrict eating
较晚进行限时饮食的人。
later in the day and that's cuz they're
这是因为他们的
eating in in in time with their body
进食时间与他们的
clocks with these millions and billions
生物钟（由数百万甚至数十亿个
of little cell
微小的细胞
clocks I have um had a weird observation
时钟控制）相符。我最近有一个奇怪的观察，
which is sometimes sort of quite rare
这种情况
these days I have to wake up super early
现在比较少见。我有时必须很早起床
to get on a flight and it means that I'm
赶飞机，这意味着我
disrupting my sleep maybe getting up at
的睡眠会被打乱，可能
4:00 or 5 in the morning and for some
凌晨四五点就得起床。出于某种
bizarre reason if I'm if I wake up at
奇怪的原因， 如果我
say 4: in the morning morning to go and
早上 4 点起床去
get a flight I am starving but if I woke
赶飞机，我会饿得不行；但如果我当天早上
up at 9: that same day I would not be I
9 点起床，我就不会饿，
would probably not get hungry till about
可能要到
2: p.m. and I've never managed to sort
下午 2 点左右才会饿。 我一直没能
of really figure out why disrupting my
真正弄明白为什么
sleep causes me to be ridiculously
睡眠被打乱会导致我异常
hungry whereas typically I don't
饥饿，而我通常不吃
honestly eat breakfast I typically eat
早餐，我一般在
about midday or 2 p.m. so I think that's
中午或下午 2 点左右吃东西。 所以我觉得这
probably a lot going on there it's
里面涉及的内容可能很多，有点超出
getting a little bit outside my of
我的
expertise but I can certainly comment
专业范围了，但我可以
from work that we've done and I'm
根据我们做过的工作以及我
familiar with so what we know is that
熟悉的领域发表一些看法。我们知道，
sleep duration sleep efficiency what we
睡眠时长、睡眠效率（
also call Sleep midpoint so the midpoint
也称为睡眠中点）会
in which you sleep impacts your hunger
影响你的饥饿感。睡眠中点会影响
levels we know that your hunger and your
你的饥饿激素和
fullness hormones change as you sleep so
饱腹激素水平。
we know that short sleepers people who
我们知道，睡眠时间短的人，比如那些
you know are getting up too early so
起得太早的人，比如
when you're getting up for your flight
赶飞机时，
then your hunger and fullness hormones
他们的饥饿激素和饱腹激素
might be perturbed and we know that
可能会受到干扰。我们知道，
short sleepers or if you've had a a poor
睡眠时间短或者睡眠质量差的人，醒来后往往比睡眠
hungry than if you've had a good night's
充足的人更饿。
sleep this isn't from my own research I
这并非我个人的研究成果（我必须对此做出保证），
always have to cavey at that but this is
但
what some of the research is showing but
一些研究表明，
that also if you've had a poor night's
睡眠质量差的人更容易选择
sleep You Reach For Less healthy food
不健康的食物。
at Kings College London by my colleagues
我的同事在伦敦国王学院进行了一项
called the Slumber study um and this
名为“睡眠研究”的研究，这项研究
really nicely illustrates how just
很好地说明了这一点。 仅仅
changing how much you sleep can change
改变睡眠时间就能改变
your dietry choices and in the Slumber
你的饮食选择。在睡眠
study they asked people who were short
研究中，研究人员要求睡眠时间短的人
sleepers to practice sleep hygiene they
养成良好的睡眠习惯，并
gave them no dietry advice they just
没有给他们任何饮食建议，只是
said practice good sleep hygiene I you
告诉他们要养成良好的睡眠习惯，比如
know no screens late at night no
深夜不要看屏幕、不要进行
physical activity caffeine alcohol Etc
体育锻炼、不要摄入咖啡因和酒精等等，保持
room and then they just monitored lots
房间黑暗。然后，研究人员监测了
of different things in these individuals
这些参与者的许多不同方面，发现
and what they found was that those who
那些
were able to extend their
能够延长
sleep actually made healthier choices
睡眠时间的人实际上做出了更健康的选择，
such that they reduced jued without
例如，他们在没有被
being told to their intake of free Sugar
告知的情况下减少了大约10克游离糖的摄入量。
by about 10 G oh really without being
真的，他们没有得到
given any
任何
advice so they slept better they atat
建议，睡眠质量更好，
less sugar they made the decision to eat
糖的摄入量也更少。他们主动决定
less sugar without being told
少吃糖，而不是被告知要这样做。
to that correlates it's it's been such a
这确实是一个很大的
revelation I think in my my life over
发现。我认为在
the last I'd say two to three years is
过去的两三年里，我
realizing the downstream impact of sleep
意识到睡眠
and a bad night's sleep cuz it was one
和睡眠不足的后续影响，这对我来说是一个很大的启示。因为这是
of the things that I think growing up
我成长过程中，
especially you as an entrepreneur when
尤其是作为一名创业者，经常
you're like consuming a lot of like
接触到各种“努力奋斗”的创业
hustle preneur you know culture and it's
文化时，就会意识到这一点。 为了
all like sacrific to sleep work seven
睡眠而牺牲工作，一周七天，
days that you assume is um take it or
你觉得这是理所当然的，或者说，
leave it like it like you assume it's
就像你认为的那样，这
often the first thing you think that you
往往是你为了追求效率而首先想到要
can sacrifice in the pursuit of
牺牲的东西。是的，
productivity yeah well this is what I I
这就是我
thought growing up and then in the last
从小到大的想法，而且
I so all I think all 20 30 olds think
我认为所有20到30岁的人都这么想。是的，
that yeah and do you not think yeah and
你不这么认为吗？
anyone that's like has I think probably
任何有一定工作压力的人，我想他们可能都会
an involuntary amount of I say
不由自主地把睡眠放在次要位置。我说“
involuntary but I mean just because of
不由自主​​”，我的意思是，仅仅是因为
the decisions they've made amount of
他们做出的决定，比如
professional pressure or like shift
工作压力、轮班
workers or anybody or even parents I
工作，或者甚至是为人父母，我
guess
想
they probably see sleep as second due to
他们可能因为生活
some other kind of priority in their
中其他更重要的事情
life and when I shifted that and I I
而把睡眠放在次要位置。当我改变这种状况，
made adjustments to my calendar and my
调整我的日程安排，
schedule to try and prioritize sleep the
努力把睡眠放在首位时，
downstream impact of it has been
它带来的后续影响是
profound in a way that I could never
深远的，这种影响我无法
measure or articulate fully but just
完全衡量或表达，但
everything seems to be better so like my
一切似乎都变得更好了，比如我和
relationships with my partner um my
伴侣的关系，我的
ability to think straight um my
思维能力，我
motivation to go to the gym that day um
那天去健身房的动力，
the work that I do everything so it's
我做的工作，所有的一切。所以，这是一个
there's been this big sort of radical
巨大的、彻底的
adjustment where I now see sleep as
改变。 现在我意识到，睡眠
actually the the starting point for all
实际上是我所有
these other choices that I make good or
其他选择（无论
bad um and that's kind of what your work
好坏）的起点。嗯，这正是你的研究重点所在。是的，
is highlighting yeah I think it's that
我认为
we have to think of these four pillars
我们必须把健康的四大支柱
together of Health we can't look at diet
结合起来考虑。我们不能单独看待饮食，
on its own can't look at sleep on its
不能单独看待睡眠，不能单独
own can't look at stress on its own we
看待压力，也
can't look at physical activity on its
不能单独看待体育锻炼。
own so if we want to improve our health
所以，如果我们想
through diet I think we must be looking
通过饮食改善健康，我认为我们必须关注
our sleep
睡眠
habits which we can to a certain extent
习惯，睡眠习惯在一定程度上是可以
control not always I know some people
控制的。我知道有些人
have to work shift some people don't
必须轮班工作，有些人别无选择，比如被
kids Etc we need to look at our stress I
孩子吵醒等等。我们需要关注压力，我
know that's one of the hardest things to
知道这是最难改变的事情之一。
change um we need to look at our
我们需要关注
physical activity and our diet and they
体育锻炼和饮食，它们之间相互
are all so interconnected and the
关联。Zoe
predict studies that were done at Zoe
进行的预测性研究
found that sleep affected metabolic
发现，睡眠对代谢
responses as much as the macronutrient
反应的影响与膳食中的宏量营养素
content of the meal what is what is that
含量一样大。这意味着什么？
what is that saying so this is some
这是
research that we published where we
我们发表的一项研究，我们
looked at people when they'd had a good
观察了人们在睡眠充足的情况下的情况。
night's sleep and we looked at people
我们研究了睡眠质量，特别是
when they'd had a bad night's sleep and
睡眠不足的人的餐后
prandial glucose response so that
血糖反应。餐后血糖反应是指，在
basically means after having your
摄入
breakfast that's got some carbohydrate
含有碳水化合物的早餐后，
in it how much does your blood glucose
血糖会
increase we call this the post frangel
升高多少。我们称之为餐后
glucose response because post prangel is
血糖反应，因为“餐后”一词源于
Greek for postmeal and so it's a term we
希腊语，意为餐后。这是一个我们
use a lot in the science and we looked
在科学研究中经常使用的术语。我们比较了睡眠充足和睡眠不足的人的
individuals postmeal glucose response
餐后血糖反应。
what we found was within the same
我们发现，
individual if they'd had a bad night
即使是同一个人，睡眠不足的人，
sleep their postmeal glucose response so
早餐后的血糖反应也比睡眠充足时
after breakfast was a lot higher
高得多。这
so what this shows I think quite nicely
很好地说明了这一点。
if we think back to what you said about
回想一下你刚才提到的，睡眠不足的人醒来后会更
how you wake up more hungry when you've
饿。我们
not had enough sleep we know that people
知道，睡眠不足会导致人们
make poor dietary choices for example
做出不良的饮食选择（例如，
from the Slumber study and then we know
睡眠研究就表明了这一点），而这些不良的饮食选择会加剧代谢反应。
are worse it just shows how you're kind
这表明，睡眠不足
of creating this perfect storm and how
和睡眠不足会形成一种恶性循环，最终导致不良的饮食习惯。
you can't think of it in isolation CU
不能孤立地看待这个问题。
firstly you're waking up and you're like
首先，你醒来后会想：
bloody hell I'm hungry secondly it's
天哪，我饿死了。其次，你可能
like I'm not having that healthy
不想吃健康的
breakfast I want that Pano shocate or
早餐，而是想吃帕诺蛋糕之类的快餐，
you know whatever that's you giving you
你知道的，就是那种能
that quick fix and then you have it and
快速解决饥饿感的食物。然后你吃了，
sugar pee compared to if you'd had a
血糖就会飙升，比起
good night's sleep and and made a
睡了个好觉，吃了
healthy choice we less hungry etc etc so
健康的食物，血糖就不会那么高。这样一来，
it's like creating this perfect storm
就像一场完美的风暴，
and it's all started with your sleep MH
而这一切都始于你的睡眠。
and that's why I don't think we can look
这就是为什么我认为我们不能
at things in isolation anymore which is
再孤立地看待问题了。
how I have spent the previous 20 years
过去20年
of my research looking at things in
我的研究都是孤立地看待问题的，
isolation but that's cuz I've not been
但那是因为我以前没有条件
had the luxury of being able to collect
收集
the kind of data that we're now
我们现在正在
collecting I get a lot of messages from
收集的那种数据。我收到很多
parents so uh because I'm not one yet I
父母的信息，因为我自己还没当父母，所以我
don't fully understand what it is to be
并不完全了解为人
a parent and the demands of Parenthood
父母是什么感觉，以及为人父母的种种要求。
so I'm going to defer to you on this cuz
所以，在这个问题上，我得听听你的意见。 因为我的
the parents my children never slept they
父母，我的孩子们从来不睡觉，他们当然
never slept they did obviously but oh my
睡了，但是我的
Lord how did you how did you survive
天哪，你是怎么熬过来的？你
that as a parent like what's the was
作为父母是怎么熬过来的？
there any strategies or tactics you put
你有没有采取什么策略或方法来
in place to defend against exactly what
应对你
you just described the downstream cont
刚才描述的
quences of sleep deprivation no because
睡眠不足带来的后果？没有，因为在
the first four years of my children's
我孩子出生的头四年里，我的
lives uh I was also I lost my father
父亲
when my um daughter a few weeks after my
也在我女儿出生几周后去世了。
daughter was born uh my sister and I
我和姐姐
became full-time carers for my mother
成了住在附近的母亲的全职照护者。
who lived around the corner um I took a
我
career break looked after my mom with my
暂停了工作，和姐姐一起照顾母亲，还要照顾
sister had two young children they
两个年幼的孩子。他们
weren't sleeping I had to show up I had
不睡觉，我必须出现，我必须
to show up to help my sister look after
出现帮姐姐照顾
my mom it was about survival
母亲。那是为了生存，我根本
I didn't think about what I ate when I
没时间考虑吃什么、什么时候
ate that was irrelevant it was about
吃，那都不重要。重要的是
survival to be there for my mom to be
生存，为了照顾母亲，为了照顾
there for my kids and whether it was
孩子。至于是不是
because asleep deprivation was also so
因为睡眠不足太
bad that it was just like driving bad
严重，导致我做出了错误的
choices I don't know but there's points
选择，我不知道。但
in time in anyone's life that we go
每个人的一生中都会有那么几个时刻，我们……
through that are about survival aren't
经历那些关乎生存的时刻，你会发现
and I think everything goes out of the
一切都变得无关紧要。
window and I'm not saying it should but
我并不是说就应该如此，但
I think that when when you're in the
我觉得，当你深陷困境时，
depths of whether it's sleep deprivation
无论是因为
because your children keeping you awake
孩子让你睡不着觉而睡眠不足，
or what I was going through you know my
还是像我经历的那样，我
mother had a de generative neurological
母亲患有退行性神经系统
condition and seeing someone daily
疾病，眼睁睁看着她每天
deterior deteriorate like
病情恶化，
that what you're doing physical activity
你根本没时间进行体育锻炼，
eating quite often doesn't become a
饮食也常常被忽略。
priority now it's probably a time it
现在，饮食或许
should be even more of a priority
更应该成为优先事项，
because we know that what you eat
因为我们知道饮食会
impacts your mental health you know
影响心理健康，
there's great research now showing how
现在有很多研究表明
important it is but when you're in that
它的重要性。但当你陷入那种迷茫的状态，无论是
depressed or you're dealing with you
抑郁、创伤
know trauma or whatever I think food is
或其他什么，我认为食物是你
one of the last things that you think
最后才会考虑的事情之一。
about making a priority and I think it's
我觉得这
okay you know when we talk about the
很正常。你知道，当我们谈到
health situation in the US and the UK
美国和英国的健康状况，比如
with obesity On The Rise and things like
肥胖率上升
that we you people are now pointing at
等等，人们现在关注的焦点是…… 把
things like a zmek as the cure for that
Zmek当作治疗方案，
but when you speak about the role there
但说到
that stress and our life styles are
压力和我们的生活方式对
having on us and I was thinking about
我们产生的影响，我一直在思考
some of the stats that have emerged
一些关于
around anxiety and young people and them
焦虑和年轻人的统计数据，尤其是
globally um maybe there's something else
全球范围内年轻人抑郁症发病率较高的情况。或许
that we should be thinking about which
我们应该考虑其他方面，
is like the mental health mindfulness
比如心理健康和正念，
choices and because you know even the
以及它们如何影响我们的饮食选择。你知道，即使是
food the ultr processed unhealthy foods
食物，那些如今备受诟病的超加工不健康食品，在
days I mean to some degree they are a
某种程度上也是
consequence also of demand oh absolutely
需求的结果。没错，
if people didn't want them no and didn't
如果人们不想要、不
buy them so maybe if we focused more on
买，他们就不会生产这些东西。所以，如果我们更多地关注
challenges we have in society people
社会中存在的心理健康挑战，人们或许就能
would have more of a um a greater
更好地
ability to make better choices
做出
themselves as well because I certainly
自己的选择。因为我亲身经历过，如果
know in my life that if I'm highly
我
stressed or if things are difficult then
压力很大或者遇到困难，
my ability to make better food choices
我做出健康饮食选择的能力
is significantly impaired yeah
就会显著下降。没错，
the research shows the Sleep the stress
研究表明，睡眠和压力都会
it impacts your ability to make choices
影响你做出各种选择的能力。
food choices you know what you're
食物的选择固然重要，但同样重要的是，你知道你在
talking about I think is so complex it's
说什么。我认为这个问题非常复杂，
where where's the responsibility for the
政府、
for the food industry where's the
食品行业、我们
responsibility for us as individuals
个人、
where's the responsibility for schools
学校（
for example or for us as parents
例如）以及我们作为父母
educating our children we need to take
教育孩子的责任分别在哪里？我们需要
into account all of those different um
考虑到所有这些不同的
areas in order to improve the foods that
方面，才能改善
we're eating there is a problem that
我们所吃的食物。问题在于，
these three dishes so the chocolate the
巧克力、饼干和薯片这三种食物似乎更
biscuits the crisps they are more tasty
美味，
or rather our taste buds our brains are
或者更确切地说，我们的味蕾和大脑
tricking us into thinking they're more
欺骗我们，让我们觉得它们更
palatable and that's a problem do we say
可口。这是一个问题。我们会对
to our children you can never ever have
孩子说“你永远不能吃
them now I've certainly never taken that
这些东西”吗？我当然从来没有采取过这种
approach I think it's all about balance
做法。我认为关键在于平衡，让
and enabling people to make the choices
人们能够做出
that they make but I recognize if I'm
他们想要的选择。但我意识到，如果我
sitting there in the evening I'm a I'm a
晚上坐在那里，
bit stressed I've got a work deadline I
有点压力，工作快到了，我
don't want to eat nuts I want to eat
不想吃坚果，我想吃
those biscuits or those crisps and I
饼干或薯片，
want a glass of wine with it I know
还想喝杯酒。我知道
that's not the right decision I know
我知道现在晚上十点了，这不是个正确的决定，
it's 10:00 at night but in the
但
moment that's the choice I probably will
当时我可能还是会这么做。
make do you get frustrated with yourself
你会不会
because you you know more about
因为自己比
nutrition than most people on planet
地球上大多数人都更懂营养，
Earth yet you still find yourself making
却仍然会做出一些
at at times suboptimal nutritional
欠佳的营养
choices no I don't because I think
选择而感到沮丧？不会，因为我觉得
that it's really quite simple when we
当我们
think about the food that we eat I think
思考自己吃的食物时，其实很简单。我觉得
we're making it so complicated and I
我们把它想得太复杂了。
think that do you know what if we eat a
如果我们吃
good amount of fruits vegetables pulses
大量的水果、蔬菜和豆类，尽量少吃
processed foods if we try and get a bit
加工食品，并且努力让
of diversity in our diet we're doing
饮食多样化，那就没问题了。
okay so what if I go and have you know
所以，如果我偶尔吃点
bared chocolate as long as I'm not doing
巧克力，只要不是
all day every day mhm and I think this
每天都吃，嗯……我觉得这种
optimization around
围绕
diet I think is taking away the pleasure
饮食的健康优化正在剥夺我们享受
of food and you know I often say if a
食物的乐趣。你知道，我常说，如果一种
food is too healthy to be enjoyed it's
食物太健康以至于无法享受，那它根本
just not healthy at all food is there to
就不健康。食物是为了给我们带来
bring us joy it's to bring us pleasure
快乐，
it's part of our emotions it's part of
它是我们情感的一部分，也是
our culture it's part of you know our
我们文化的一部分。 这是我们
social connections MH and I worry that
社交关系的一部分，MH，我担心
now there's a certain proportion of
现在
society so hyperfocused
社会上有一部分人过度关注
on that 1% gain in terms of the food
饮食中那1%的提升，以至于
that they're eating that they forget all
忘记了享受美食带来的
of that pleasure so I think I have quite
乐趣。所以我认为我的
a balanced approach because I know that
方法比较平衡，因为我知道，
ultimately if you get the foundations
最终，如果你打好了基础，其他的一切
right the rest will follow but that
都会随之而来。而基础就占了
95% of what makes a food or a diet and
食物或饮食的95%，
that's how we need to think about what
这就是我们应该如何看待
we healthy what do you think of
健康饮食的方式。你对各种
diets um because there's so many bloody
饮食有什么看法？嗯，因为市面上有太多乱七八糟的饮食方法，
there I think
我认为营养学、
Nutrabolics there is so much
营养素之类的东西也很多，充斥着太多
misinformation out there what you see on
错误信息。你在
social media versus what the evidence
社交媒体上看到的内容和实际证据简直
shows is like night and day I mean
天壤之别，我是
seriously and so when I think about diet
认真的。所以，当我想到饮食时，我的
my view on
看法是，有些饮食方法有
some good evidence you know eat plant
很好的证据支持，比如吃植物性食物，
eat 30 plants a week yeah that's great
每周吃30种植物，这很棒。
um go on a low calorie diet to lose
低卡路里饮食减肥也
weight great but how are you going to
很好，但是如何
maintain that weight that's a whole
维持体重呢？这又是
other question great for losing not for
另一个问题了。减肥当然很好。 不是为了
maintenance um then you've got the
维持健康，嗯，还有
alkaline diet I mean I I don't
碱性饮食。我的意思是，我不明
understand that eat alkaline foods but
白吃碱性食物，但
your stomach is acidic so got no idea
胃是酸性的，所以我完全不知道它是
how that works the blood type
怎么起作用的。血型
diet I don't actually know what half of
饮食，我其实不知道
these diets do because I do not
这些饮食方法有一半是做什么的，因为我不懂
physiological theory behind them and so
它们背后的生理理论。
do you know what though Stephen I think
你知道吗，斯蒂芬，我觉得
if it works for you as an individual
如果这些方法对你个人
fine do it but if it works for you at
有效，那就去做吧。但如果它让你失去了享受
of the pleasure of food at the expense
美食的乐趣，失去了
of enjoying life to the fullness that's
充分享受生活的机会，
what I think is a shame like Tim
我觉得那就太可惜了。就像蒂姆说的，
restricted eating I think there's great
限制饮食。我认为
eating now much of it comes from very
现在有很多关于限时饮食的证据，其中很多来自
tightly metabolically controlled studies
代谢控制非常严格的临床研究。
you know that are done Clinic where
你知道，这些研究让
people you know eat within a five or six
受试者在五六个小时内进食，
hour window so they have their first
比如第一
meal at 10: their last meal at 4 in the
顿饭在晚上10点，最后一顿饭在下午4点。研究发现，限时饮食可以
evening reduces inflammation reduces
减少炎症，减轻
body weight improves blood cholesterol
体重，改善血液胆固醇
etc etc
等等。
etc I don't want to only eat six hours a
我不想一天只吃六个小时，我
day I want to have dinner with my family
想和家人一起吃晚饭，我想
I want to have dinner with my friends I
和朋友一起吃晚饭，我想
want to go to the PB in the evening not
晚上去PB（可能不是
every evening I want to live
每天晚上），我想好好
life so what can we do that takes that
生活。所以呢？ 我们能做到吗？这遵循了那种
principle of that diet
饮食原则，
but we still benefit from
但我们仍然能从中受益。
it and this is what's great again about
这正是
the research that we're doing at zo
我们在ZO进行的研究的伟大之处。
we've done this study called the bigf
我们进行了一项名为“
study the big intermittent fasting study
大型间歇性断食研究”（BIGF）的研究，
we had 150,000 people sign up and we
共有15万人参与。
said look we want to see if what we find
我们想看看
in tightly controlled clinical studies
在严格控制的临床研究中发现的结果是否适用
plays out in the real world because we
于现实世界，因为我们
always have to think how does all of
总是要思考所有
this evidence play out in the real world
这些证据在现实世界中如何体现，它们是否
does it matter and we said just limit
重要。我们建议将
your eating window so the time from your
进食窗口（即从
first to your last meal to 10 hours so
第一餐到最后一餐的时间）限制在10小时内。
that means if you're having your first
这意味着，如果
meal at 10: you're having in the morning
你早上10点吃第一餐，
you're having your last meal at 8 in the
晚上8点吃最后一餐。嗯，对吧？
sure my paral cannot do maths um that's
我的朋友数学不好。嗯，这对
quite doable for most people I can have
大多数人来说都很容易做到。我可以
my breakfast at 10:00 I can finish my
10点吃早餐，晚上
last meal at 8 I mean yeah I do like
8点吃最后一餐。是的，我喜欢在
munching on my chocolate late at night I
深夜吃巧克力，我
could probably still live a happy enough
可能仍然可以过得很开心。
life doing that and we found people
我们发现，人们确实
could do it we found as well that people
可以做到这一点。我们也发现，那些
who practiced it within two weeks they
坚持两周的人
felt better they had better energy
感觉更好了，精力更充沛，
better mood um you know they were
心情也更好了。你知道，他们
feeling a lot better they also lost
感觉好多了，而且体重也减轻了。
weight many people wanted to do this
很多人想尝试这种方法就是为了
because they wanted to lose weight and
减肥。
we actually see from evidence that
事实上，我们从证据中看到，
even if they're told not to change their
即使被告知不要改变
calorie intake just by limiting the
卡路里摄入量，仅仅通过限制
eating window on average reduce the
进食窗口，人们在限时进食时平均也能减少
energy intake by about 300 calories on
约300卡路里的能量摄入。
this um conversation around fasting
关于禁食和
calorie restriction and some people say
卡路里限制，一直存在着很大的争论。有些人认为
that it's basically the same thing and
这本质上是一样的，而且在
that you've kind of proven that to some
某种程度上，你已经证明了这一点。
degree so we know that in most instances
所以我们知道，在大多数情况下，
if you practice time restricted eating
如果你进行限时进食，
you unintentionally reduce your energy
你会在不知不觉中减少能量
intake and the data shows that on
摄入。数据显示，
average from the studies that published
根据已发表的研究，平均而言，
is about 300 calories obviously depends
大约减少300卡路里。当然，
on the duration the reduction in body
体重减轻的程度取决于持续时间。
weight also we know is dependent on the
我们也知道，体重减轻还取决于
eating window so the smaller the eating
进食窗口的大小，进食窗口越短，
body weight but there have been some
体重减轻越多。但也有一些
studies that actually control the amount
研究实际上控制了
of calories that people eat but have
人们的卡路里摄入量，但
some people having it in a bigger eating
有些人的进食窗口更大。 进食
window some in a smaller eating window
窗口：有些人会选择较短的进食窗口。
and what these Studies have shown that
研究表明，
if you have the same amount of calories
即使摄入的卡路里总量相同，
but you change the period in time in
但改变进食时间，也能
an additional benefit on metabolic
对代谢健康带来额外益处，例如改善
blood lipids in terms of inflammation
血脂和炎症，而这些益处与
independent of calories Okay so
卡路里摄入量无关。所以，
Tim restricted eating has some benefit
限制卡路里摄入确实有一些益处，但
consumption yes but the bulk of the
大部分益处都源于卡路里的减少。因此，限制卡路里摄入本身确实有
calories so there's some benefit
一些益处，但
bulk of the benefit that we see is due
我们观察到的大部分益处都
to a subconscious or unintentional
源于潜意识或无意的
reduction in calories and I think this
卡路里减少。我认为，
is when we're thinking about diets I
当我们考虑节食方法时，
think we need to think about how easy is
需要考虑
it to implement is there any evidence
它的可操作性，以及是否有科学依据。99
behind it and 99% there isn't for the
% 的节食方法都没有科学依据。即使是
ones that there is evidence like Tim
像
restricted eating can we do it in a way
限制卡路里摄入这样有科学依据的节食方法，我们能否以一种可持续的方式进行，从而维持正常的
that still enables us to live our life
生活方式？
point I think is really important
我认为可持续性这一点非常重要，
because there's now some new evidence
因为现在有一些新的证据表明，饮食习惯的一致性对健康至关重要，
emerging around consistency MH and the
而且
importance of consistent eating
饮食
patterns and I think this is fascinating
模式的一致性非常重要。我认为这很吸引人。
so there's research showing that if one
有研究表明，如果
day you're having three meals and then
你某天摄入大量卡路里，那么你接下来几天的饮食习惯可能会发生变化。 一天三顿正餐，第二天
the next day you're having nine Mees and
九顿，
the next day say you're having six meals
第三天六顿，
and the next day you're having four
第四天四顿，这样
meals that troubles your body it's like
你的身体会感觉很不适应。你会想：
whoa hold on I'm used to having you know
等等，我习惯
four eating events a day and this is
一天吃四顿饭。这一点很
important to bear in mind when we think
重要，尤其是在考虑
about snacking if you're typically a
零食的时候。如果你平时就喜欢吃零食，那就继续
snacker then fine carry on snacking as
吃吧，
long as it's on healthy food and as long
只要是健康食品，并且
as you have your last snack before 9: at
最后一次零食要在晚上九点之前吃完。如果
night if you're not a snacker having me
你平时不吃零食，虽然我刚才已经
just vouched for the great benefits of
强调了吃
snacking don't start snacking because
零食的好处，但你还是不要开始吃零食，因为
you don't want to be
你不想作息不
inconsistent and this new evidence
规律。现在有新的证据表明，
emerging around the consistency of
规律的
eating and there's some research done
饮食习惯非常重要，而且早在很久以前就有人做过相关研究，
started this idea I think is really
我认为这个观点非常
fascinating so try and have a consistent
有趣。所以，尽量保持规律的
eating pattern same applies to sleep try
饮食习惯。睡眠也一样，尽量每天在同一时间
and go to bed at the same time get up at
睡觉，同一时间起床。
the same time we've done some work uh
我们之前也研究过“
around social jet lag don't know if
社交时差”，不知道
you've heard of that term uh I think
你有没有听说过这个词，我想
I've heard of it what does it mean so
我听说过。
social jet lag is where you have an
社交时差是指
the week so for example for many maybe
一周内睡眠模式不规律。例如，很多
20-year old or students they might go to
20岁左右的年轻人或学生，可能工作日
bed at a sensible time in the week and
按时睡觉，
go parting and crazy at the weekend or
周末则外出玩乐、疯狂玩乐。像我这样的
for someone like myself I go to bed late
人，
at night because I'm late night working
因为工作、照顾孩子等原因，晚上睡得很晚，周末
catch up so if you have more than about
再补觉。如果你工作日和周末的睡眠时间相差超过
a one and a half
一个半
hour uh increase or decrease in sleep
小时，这就是
Etc that's called social jet lag MH so
所谓的社交时差。
it's a bit like jet lag going from one
它有点像从一个
country to the other and what we know is
国家到另一个国家时产生的时差。我们
and we've published on this from our own
自己的
zo predict research people who
Zo-Predict研究表明，
experience social jet lag so have this
经历社交时差的人，也就是
inconsistent sleeping pattern make poor
睡眠模式不规律的人，往往
dietary
饮食
choices they have more inflammation they
习惯不良，炎症水平更高，
have a different gut microbiome
肠道菌群组成也不同。虽然
the dietary choices but again it just
饮食习惯可能与此有关，但这再次印证了
plays into this whole idea that we're
我们之前
talking about that we can't just think
讨论的观​​点：我们不能仅仅因为……就认为……
about the food in isolation we need to
关于隔离期间的食物，我们需要
think about how we're eating out our
思考一下我们的饮食习惯、
lifestyle Etc what else is on your
生活方式等等。你的“营养代谢”清单上还有什么？你会想到哪些
lot of people believe I mean there's a
很多人都认同的观点？我的意思是，
big debate raging at the moment about
目前关于
seed oils because we had uh incoming um
植物油的争论非常激烈，因为一位……嗯……
American I guess he's a politician um
美国人，我猜他是一位政治家，小
RFK Jr say recently seed oils are one of
罗伯特·肯尼迪最近说，植物油是食品中
the most unhealthy ingredients that we
最不健康的成分之一。
have in foods and the reason they're in
它们之所以出现在
Foods is because they're heavily
食品中，是因为它们受到大量
subsidized they're very cheap but they
补贴，价格非常便宜，但它们
are associated with all kinds of very
与各种非常
serious illnesses including body-wide
严重的疾病有关，包括
inflammation which affects all of our
影响我们所有人
health it's one of the worst things you
健康的全身炎症。这是你能吃到的最糟糕的东西之一，
if you eat any processed food sorry I'm
如果你吃任何加工食品，几乎不可能避免摄入植物油。抱歉，我
laugh to laugh this is like Nutrabolics
忍不住笑了，这简直是“营养代谢”的延伸，
Beyond Nutrabolics but please I that's
但请相信我，
basically it he said if you're eating
基本上就是这样。他说，如果你吃
any processed food you're going to be
任何加工食品，你就会
eating seed oils and he advocates for
摄入植物油，他提倡用牛油
replacing seed oils with beef Tallow
代替植物油。
which is in the UK is referred to as
在英国，牛油被称为“
dripping which is pure beef fat and is a
滴油”，它是纯牛肉。 脂肪，而且是
saturated fat and he's actually selling
饱和脂肪，他现在居然在卖印着小
T-shirts um RFK Jr at the moment that
罗伯特·肯尼迪头像的T恤，上面写着“
again so what so seed oils what is this
再次用牛油制作煎炸油”。那么，种子油呢？
weird debate that I've seen raging on on
我在
my Instagram about seed oils I've like
Instagram上看到关于种子油的这场奇怪的争论到底是怎么回事？我一直
managed to avoid it like I've just not
设法避开它，就像我根本没
paid attention to it but I see the word
注意过一样，但
seed oils all of a sudden everywhere
突然间到处都能看到“种子油”这个词。
okay so seed oils I think is at the top
好吧，种子油我认为在营养
of the neutr bolics list I I it blows my
清单上名列前茅。
mind what you've just read me it
你刚才读到的内容让我震惊，真的太令人震惊了。
seriously blows mind I've done lots of
我
research on seed oils so I can talk from
对种子油做了很多研究，所以我可以根据
my own research as well as all the
我自己的研究以及所有现有的
evidence spaces out there there is
证据来谈谈我的看法。
absolutely no evidence that is credible
绝对没有任何可信的证据，
evidence when interpreted in the correct
如果以正确的
way to show seed oils are
方式解读，可以证明种子油
harmful what is a seed oil so a seed oil
有害。什么是种子油？种子油
is an oil from a seed so the most common
是从种子中提取的油。英国最常见的
seed oils in the UK is rape seed oil
种子油是菜籽油，
which is also known as canola oil in the
在
US and many other countries followed by
美国和许多其他国家也被称为卡诺拉油，其次是
sunflow oil the most common seed oils in
葵花籽油。美国最常见的种子油
the US are soybean oil followed by rape
是…… 大豆油、
seed or oil followed by sunflower seed
菜籽油或葵花籽油，
arguments that people use to say that
人们通常用三四种理由来证明
seedor are bad for us and if you go on
种子对我们有害。如果你去
social media I mean this is a perfect
社交媒体看看，你会发现
scientific evidence and what's on social
科学证据和社交
media if you go on social media seedor
媒体上的说法截然不同。社交媒体上充斥着各种谣言，比如种子
are toxic seedor are going to give you
有毒、会导致
Alzheimer's seedor are going to give you
阿尔茨海默病、会导致
cancer seedar are going to kill
癌症、会要命等等。但事实恰恰相反。
have sensible boring scientists like me
像我这样理智的科学家也会说种子对身体有益，你
could put that as one of your assets or
可以把这作为宣传卖点，
whatever you call it or adverts for this
或者说是广告。比如，我们可以
m so we could say seedor are really good
说种子对身体有益，或者说种子
seedles are toxic they're going to kill
有毒，会要命，好像
you everyone's trying to kill us with
每个人都想用种子害死我们似的。但哪种说法更能吸引眼球呢？
probably the toxic seed oil narrative
可能是“种子油有毒”的说法。
and so the sensible science there's no
所以，理智的科学不会像某些人说的那样，用
crazy inflammatory argument the sensible
疯狂的煽动性言论来掩盖真相。
science isn't going to get the click so
为了吸引点击量，很
unfortunately the voices of reason and
不幸，那些理性的声音——
often it comes from boring academics
通常来自
like myself not saying other academics
像我这样略显枯燥的学者（我并不是说其他​​学者
are boring but sensible academics like
枯燥，而是像我这样理智的学者，他们能提供
balance we we don't get a voice we're
平衡）——却被忽视了，我们的声音
not being heard which is one of the
没有被听到。这也是
reasons that you know I wanted to come
我来参加
on this show because of the
这个节目的原因之一，因为存在很多
misinformation and we have to get the
错误信息。我们必须让
voice of reason out there we have to get
理性的声音被听到，我们必须让
the voice of reason so things like that
理性的声音被听到。像
to do with seed alls are not what's
种子油这类事情并没有
dominating the
占据
headlines so what people say in terms of
新闻头条。人们谈到
seedor is firstly our intake of seedor
种子油时，首先是说，过去20、30、40、50年里，我们的种子油摄入量
has increased 100 fold the last 20 30 40
增加了100倍。
50 years and with that increase in seed
随着种子
oil intake so has cancer increased so
油摄入量的增加，癌症、
has cardiovascular disease increased so
心血管疾病、
has obesity increased so has Alzheimer's
肥胖症、阿尔茨海默病
etc etc so must be to do the SE oils
等等的发病率也增加了。所以一定是种子油的缘故。那么，
well what else has changed in that 50
这50年里还有哪些变化呢？
years we're more sedent we eat loads of
我们变得更加久坐不动，我们吃了很多
these other it's heavily processed foods
其他高度加工的食品，
in you know the sugar the this the that
里面含有各种各样的成分，比如糖等等。
so much else has changed you know you
你知道，情况已经发生了变化，你
can't put it all down to the fact that
不能把所有原因都归结于
at that point in time seed oils were
当时种子油也在发生
also changing we also know that about
变化。我们也知道，
60% of the seed oil that we eat is
我们摄入的种子油中约有60%
actually in these heavily processed
实际上存在于这些高度加工的
unhealthy Foods so it's the first
不健康食品中。这是
argument they say and you see these
他们提出的第一个论点。你会看到
beautiful figures that they put out
他们公布的那些漂亮的图表，
where you see on one axis the intake of
一个轴代表
cedor you see on the other axis um you
种子油的摄入量，另一个轴代表……
know uh o over time you'll see uh for
随着时间的推移，你会看到……
example like rates of cancer and you see
例如，癌症发病率，你会看到
rates of cancer or rates of
癌症发病率或
cardiovascular disease going up lineally
心血管疾病发病率
with the intake of seed oil but we have
与种子油摄入量呈线性增长。但我们必须
to think what else has changed in that
思考，在那段
time the other arguments that they use
时间里还有哪些其他变化。他们使用的其他论点
are theoretical arguments based on
是基于
biochemical Pathways and I spend an hour
生物化学途径的理论论点。我花了一个小时
teaching this to our undergrad and I'm
给我们的本科生讲解这些内容，我
not going to bore you with that
不会用
biochemical
生物化学
part but they talk about the ratio of um
部分来让你感到厌烦。他们谈到了
a particular fatty acid which is Omega 6
某种特定脂肪酸（例如
which is found in high levels in seed
在种子
oils and omega-3 which is another fatty
油中含量很高的ω-6脂肪酸）和ω-3
acid and they talk about how having lots
脂肪酸的比例。他们谈到，大量
of seedles changes this ratio makes uh
食用种子油会改变这种比例，从而导致……
this pro-inflammatory state because it
促炎状态是因为它会
increases a particular Downstream
增加某些下游
chemicals etc etc
化学物质等等。
what we know from kind of theoretical
我们从理论上的
biochemical Pathways and enzymes Etc
生化途径和酶等方面了解到，这些机制
doesn't actually play out in humans
实际上并不适用于人体。
we're so clever we have all of these
我们非常聪明，拥有各种
mechanisms in place to control
机制来控制
inflammation to control oxidative stress
炎症、控制氧化应激、
to control Downstream impacts of foods
控制食物的下游影响。
and so this argument that is also used
因此，这种
to say that Omega six fatty acids so the
认为ω-6脂肪酸（
main fat that's found in many of these
许多种子油中的主要脂肪）具有
seed ORS is pro-inflammatory
促炎作用的论点
is not supported by any evidence it's
没有任何证据支持，也
not supported by tightly controlled
没有严格控制的
clinical trials if anything it's shown
临床试验支持。相反，ω-6脂肪酸已被证明
to be anti-inflammatory that levels of
具有抗炎作用，
in inflammatory um circulating Mo
炎症性循环氧
molecules actually
分子的水平实际上会
reduce and yet they use this kind of
降低。然而，他们却使用这种
theoretical argument or what they've
理论论证，或者说是他们
seen in a Petri dish for example or in a
在培养皿或试管中观察到的结果。
test tube so where is this narrative
那么，这种关于种子油有毒的说法是从哪里来的？
come from where where did it originate
它起源于哪里？
it just one of those things that just
难道只是像
snowball I think it's one of those
滚雪球一样越滚越大吗？我认为正是如此。
things that snowball and I think it does
而且，我认为它与
people are using against old processed
人们用来反对旧加工
food it does fit in with other other
食品的论点不谋而合。 还有一些其他的
narratives that are going on I think
说法，我认为
some people can be very clever in
有些人很擅长
cherry-picking research so there's a
断章取义地引用研究。
study called the Sydney har study and in
比如悉尼·哈尔研究，
this study this was done in the 70s and
这项研究是在70年代进行的，
this is a study that's used often to
经常被用来
advocate for the toxic effects of seed
佐证植物油的毒性。
oils and in this study uh males that had
这项研究中，一些曾发生过
had a heart event or a heart attack of
心脏病或
sorts uh were uh randomly allocated to
类似心脏病发作的男性被随机分配到两个组：一组通过大量食用植物油来
either increase um
增加饮食中的
their omega-6 so this particular type of
ω-6脂肪酸（这种
fatty acid that we is in seed oils um in
脂肪酸存在于植物油中）；另一组则被
or they were asked to just follow their
要求保持
normal diet which is quite high in
正常的饮食习惯，即摄入大量
saturated fat and what they found is
饱和脂肪。研究发现，
those that increased their seed oil
增加植物油
intake went on to have worse Health
摄入量的人健康状况更差。
outcomes now the problem with that is is
问题在于，
that in those days the majority of seed
当时大多数
oils underwent an industrial process
植物油都经过一种
called partial
叫做部分
hydrogenation and partial hydrogenation
氢化的工业加工过程，而部分氢化会
produces a very harmful fat called trans
产生一种叫做反式脂肪的有害脂肪。
fats you might have heard of trans heard
你可能听说过反式脂肪，对吧？
of the word yeah and so they were eating
所以，这些男性食用的
this seed oil in the form of a margarine
植物油是以人造黄油
or fat spread that had undergone partial
或涂抹酱的形式存在的。 经过部分
hydrogenation and therefore was full of
氢化，因此富含
trans fats trans fats increase
反式脂肪。反式脂肪会增加
cholesterol trans fats increase
胆固醇，加剧
inflammation trans fats are bad fast
炎症，反式脂肪有害健康，这就是
that's why they are not in our food
为什么它们不再出现在我们的食物
supply
供应中。
anymore and so of course that seed oil
所以，这种种子油当然会
was going to cause worse Health outcomes
导致更糟糕的健康后果，
but it's not how seed oil is consumed
但现在人们食用种子油的方式已经不同了。
now and so it's that clever cherry
因此，很多所谓的营养学观点往往是被巧妙地
picking of evidence that often supports
选择性地引用证据支持的。
there yeah and you know people
是的，
you know with all these studies out
你知道，现在有很多研究，其中一些
there and with some studies having less
研究的严谨性较低，
of the randomized control element or
或者缺乏随机对照试验。或者说，缺乏随机对照
what's the other term for a study where
试验的另一个术语是什么？
they do um they look at like 50 studies
他们一次性查看50项研究，
at once so they're met analysis we do
所以这些研究都不符合标准。我们进行的是
randomized control trials so these will
随机对照试验，这类
be trials where there's always a control
试验总会有一个对照
arm will randomly allocate some people
组，随机将一些人分配
to an intervention like seed oils and
到干预组（例如食用种子油），另一些
some people to control could be
人分配到对照组（例如食用
saturated fat could be beef Tallow
饱和脂肪或牛油）。
that's been done and then we look at
然后，我们观察
different Health outcomes we follow them
不同的健康结果，并对他们进行
over a period of time or it could be
一段时间的跟踪，或者
that I ask you for a month to have seed
我可能会要求你观察一个月。
oils and then next month have beef
下个月我们会
Tallow for example and then we'll look
研究植物油，例如牛油。然后我们会比较
at different Health outcomes compare how
不同的健康结果，看看
you responded to one versus the other
你对这两种油的反应有何不同。
and then what we do as scientists is if
作为科学家，如果
there's enough of these clinical trials
这类临床试验（即
these randomized control trials we put
随机对照试验）足够多，我们会将
them all together into what's called a
它们汇总起来进行
metaanalysis and we look what does the
荟萃分析，看看
metaanalysis show so for example for
荟萃分析的结果如何。例如，对于
seedor there's met analysis for example
植物油，有一项荟萃分析，其中包含
of um about
大约
42 uh randomized control trials where
42 项随机对照试验，这些试验
they comp seed oils to other fats
比较了植物油和其他脂肪，结果
showing consistently that there is no
一致表明植物油没有
harmful benefit that actually there's a
有害益处，实际上还能
reduction in cardiovascular disease
降低心血管疾病的风险，
because the particular fat that's in
因为植物油中的特定脂肪
seed oil has a really potent cholesterol
具有非常有效的
lowering effect so it's actually
降低胆固醇的作用，所以它实际上
beneficial for our health yet beef
对我们的健康有益。而牛油
Tallow is full of saturated Fair it's
富含饱和脂肪，
full of ptic acid which is a particular
富含对乙酰氨基酚酸，这是一种
type of saturated fat that we know is
我们知道
bad for us there has been studies and
对我们有害的饱和脂肪。
these studies were done many years ago
多年前的一些研究比较了
comparing seedor with beef Tallow seedor
植物油和牛油，结果显示植物油
always were came out better seedor
总是更好。植物油
always reduce cholesterol compared to
总是能降低胆固醇，
beef Tallow reduced inflammation Etc
减少炎症等等。
reduced cardiovascular risk factors
降低心血管风险因素，
you're very passionate about this I am
你对此充满热情，我也是，
because I've researched I as a research
因为我作为一名
active scientist where I've run
活跃的科研人员，做过
randomized control Charles and I tell
随机对照试验。查尔斯，我告诉
you what you sweat Blood and Tears I
你，这需要付出多少汗水和泪水。我
love my research but it's bleming hard
热爱我的研究，但
work doing a clinical trial you know
临床试验真的非常辛苦。你知道，
getting ethical approval recruiting
获得伦理批准、招募
people changing people's diet running
受试者、改变受试者的饮食、开展
dietary studies is really hard because
饮食研究等等，都非常困难。因为
it's not a case of giving them a pill if
这不像给他们吃药那么简单。如果
I'm going to give you seedor I've got to
我要给你服用某种补充剂，我必须
think well how am I going to do that
思考：我该怎么做？
what am I what instead of what what am I
我该从
taking out of your diet to give you that
你的饮食中去除什么？
how am I going to make sure the rest of
我该如何确保你
your diet is control so once you run
饮食的其他部分得到控制？所以，当你
studies yourself and you sweat at that
自己做完研究，为此付出了
blood and tears and then you see this
汗水和泪水之后，再看到
nutriol this misinformation out there
市面上充斥着营养学方面的错误信息，真的非常令人
it's really bloody frustrating but it's
沮丧。但值得庆幸的是，像你这样的
a good thing that people like yourself
人
are leaning into the mediums now of like
现在开始利用
podcasting because it's worth saying
播客等媒介，因为就
transfer of information it's typically
信息传播而言，通常情况下，那些
people who have either a platform or who
拥有平台、
are great public speakers or great sales
善于演讲或拥有……的人才能做到。
people that are ultimately going to like
最终，那些能够最有效地传播
with their information irrespective of
信息、最能引起共鸣的销售人员，无论
whether that information is is credible
这些信息是否可信，都能获得最广泛的传播。
so it's good to see more and more people
因此，很高兴看到越来越多的研究人员走出
laboratory and coming into environments
实验室，进入
where they can provide counteracting
能够提供反驳
information and as someone that's on my
信息的领域。作为一名正在探索自我的人，我需要梳理
through all of this information to find
所有这些信息，找到最
out what's right for me um it's
适合自己的方法。这很
difficult and for a lot of people it's
困难，对很多人来说尤其如此。我的方法是，
kind of my own framework for this is I
我会
listen to things and then I don't don't
倾听各种信息，但我并不一定完全
necessarily trust one source to be true
相信某个信息来源的真实性。我会
but I I I almost like wait
关注信息的
the authority experience and the rigor
权威性、经验以及他们获取信息的严谨性。
information and then I guess I perform
然后，我会对与
different people that I speak to and
我交谈过的人、
guests and information that I get to
嘉宾以及我收集到的信息进行综合分析，
find the sweet spots where the sweet
找到那些
that I think have a lot of sort of rigor
我认为在相关领域拥有丰富经验、
and authority and um
权威性和严谨性的观点。
then I accept it to be true whereas I'm
那么我就接受它是真的，但我
not going to go on Instagram and see a
不会去Instagram上看到一个
real popup in it says that I don't know
弹窗说往
putting sugar in your eyeballs is good
眼球里塞糖是好事，
and I'm not going to crack on with it
我不会仅仅
just because the person's got Charisma
因为那个人很有魅力就盲目跟风。
and I think in the world we live in
我认为在我们生活的这个信息
where there is now this decentralization
分散化的世界里，
its downsides we all need to have our
有利有弊，我们都需要有
own decision framework um set aside what
自己的决策框架，暂且不论真假。
is true but I think yours is more
但我认为你的框架
rigorous than most so many people get
比大多数人的都更严谨。很多人只
their information from One Source many
从一个来源获取信息，很多
people trust one source
人只信任一个来源。
and you're right that as academics we're
你说得对，作为学者，我们
rarely given a platform yeah and this is
很少有机会发声。是的，这正是我
I've done at Zoe well being able to do
在Zoe工作中最看重的一点：能够开展
the kind of trials that we're doing but
我们正在进行的这类试验，以及
being able to have a platform not just
拥有一个平台，不仅
for me but for us to invite other
对我个人而言，也对我们所有人来说，可以邀请其他
credible scientists onto the Zoe podcast
有影响力的科学家参加Zoe的播客节目，
or for me to come on to this kind of
或者让我自己参加这类
podcast we're not trained as academics
播客节目。我们作为学者，接受的训练不是如何
how to communicate we're trained how
沟通，而是如何
to you know run good studies in my case
开展优秀的科研工作。就我而言，是如何
you know run clinical trials interpret
开展…… 临床试验解读
the evidence evaluate the evidence
证据、评估证据、
critique the evidence and you know I'm
批判证据，你知道，我是
selftaught to present the evidence to
自学成才，学会了如何向
other
其他
academics but we're not taught to
学者展示证据，但我们并没有接受过如何向
communicate it to the general public so
公众传播这些证据的培训。所以，
for me it's been a journey working at
在Zoe工作对我来说是一段漫长的旅程，我一直在
Zoe of trying to communicate really
努力传达一些非常
complex stuff like I would have loved to
复杂的信息。比如，我很想花
have spent an hour telling you about the
一个小时跟你讲讲
biochemical pathway of why um seed oil
为什么种子油
don't impact inflammation yeah but I
不会影响炎症的生化途径，但我
know that really you're not interested
知道你和听众其实都不
the listeners aren't interested but you
感兴趣。但
know I'm hoping that by informing them
我希望通过告知他们
that I've done these studies and that
我做过这些研究，以及
these are the results there's trust that
这些研究结果，能够让他们相信
actually what we found is true but we're
我们发现的是正确的。但我们这些
research active scientists partly
活跃的科研人员的声音微弱，部分原因是
because of time you know I'm I'm still
时间有限，你知道，我还在进行
in you know running trials running uh
试验，进行
you know different
各种
interventions but also
干预，但
I think many of the big
我认为很多大型
platforms aren't giving us the
平台并没有给我们
opportunity necessarily
机会，
because we haven't got the most exciting
因为我们没有最激动人心的
things to say because at the end of the
内容可讲。毕竟，我们最终
day you know we'll present the evidence
会呈现证据，我们
we'll present it with caveat we'll
会谨慎地
present it with
呈现，并附加一些注意事项。
caution and you know I will always say
你知道，我总是会像
on as I were to students I'm teaching
对学生那样说，我
what I'm telling you now is based on
现在所讲的都是基于现有
what the evidence shows now in 10 years
证据，十年后
time I might be totally wrong MH all of
我可能就完全错了。所有
these trials showing seedor are fine I
这些试验都表明 Seedor 没问题，但
might be wrong in 10 years time I mean I
十年后我可能就错了。我的意思是，我对此表示
doubt it I doubt it because there's
怀疑，因为
enough research but as scientists that's
研究已经足够多了。但作为科学家，
something else you know we we always
我们总是会对此有所保留，你知道，
caveat with and I think sometimes that's
有时这对
difficult for the general public maybe I
公众来说很难理解。也许我这么
mean I might be doing a disservice I
说会误导大家。我
don't know that you have the nonactive
不知道你们有没有那些不活跃的
SC or or non-active influencers science
科学界人士，或者不活跃的科学界意见
influencers I don't know what you call
领袖，我不知道该怎么称呼
them that speak with such certainty now
他们，他们说话如此肯定。
I will if it's my study so I'll talk
如果是我自己的研究，我会很
with certainty over the seedor study
肯定地谈论 Seedor 研究，
because I've done them I've been there
因为我做过，我
in the lab analyzing it or I'll speak
在实验室里分析过数据；或者我会很
with certainty over snacking data
肯定地谈论零食数据，
because I've you know sweat Blood and
因为我为了
Tears over you know running the stats
统计
Etc but I won't talk with certainty
等等付出了无数心血。但我不会
about anything else that I haven't done
对任何我没有亲自做过的事情妄下断言。
myself and yet you have other people
然而，你 其他人
talk with such certainty and I think
如此自信地谈论这件事，我认为这
that's what instills confidence in maybe
或许能给
listeners and that's why they get more
听众带来信心，也可能是节目
viewers if you you've been thinking of
收视率高的原因。如果你一直想
starting your own business I want to
创业，我想借此机会
take a moment to nudge you into action
鼓励你行动起来。
this is the month to begin and my show
这个月就是开始的最佳时机。我的节目
sponsor Shopify has made it easy enough
赞助商 Shopify 让将你
to turn that business idea in your head
脑海中的商业想法变成
into a reality so if you've got the idea
现实变得轻而易举。所以，如果你已经有了想法，
Shopify has the tools they remove all of
Shopify 拥有各种工具，可以帮你消除开设在线业务
the hurdles that usually come when
时通常会遇到的所有障碍。
launching an online business with
凭借
thousands of customizable templates and
数千个可定制的模板和
intuitive tools you can launch a global
直观的工具，你可以
storefront in minutes reaching customers
在几分钟内搭建一个全球网店，触达
all over the world and here's the kicker
世界各地的客户。更重要的是，
all your sales channels are in one place
你所有的销售渠道都集中在一个平台上，
including any social media marketplaces
包括你想销售的任何社交媒体平台。最后，
you want to sell through so I'll leave
我想问
you with this question how will you feel
你一个问题：
if a year from now you're still in the
如果一年后你仍然原地踏步，你会作何感想？
same spot the time is now to take that
现在就是迈出那一步，
trial at shopify.com
在 shopify.com 注册每月 1 美元的试用期的最佳时机。
Bartlet that's shopify.com
巴特利特，就是 shopify.com。
Bartlet there's a lot of neutr bolics
巴特利特，周围有很多中性波，对吧？
Around Da right yep um I think the
嗯，我认为目前
prevailing Nutrabolics is that Dair is
主流的营养学观点是乳制品
bad for you yep so there's not lots of
对人体有害。是的，所以
Nutrabolics around Dairy and it's
关于乳制品的营养学研究并不多，而且这与
saturated fat so as a whole we know
饱和脂肪的营养学研究也有关联。我们都知道
saturated fat is bad for us Dairy
饱和脂肪对人体有害，而乳制品是
UK so therefore we could say all Dair is
英国饱和脂肪摄入的主要来源。因此，我们可以说所有乳制品都
bad for us but no Dairy is a diverse
对人体有害，但事实并非如此。乳制品种类繁多，包括奶酪、酸奶、黄油、
yogurt you've got butter you've got milk
牛奶等等。
and how they impact our health is vastly
它们对我们健康的影响
different depending on whether it's a
差异很大，取决于它们是
liquid a solid it's fermented it's
液体还是固体，
non-fermented etc etc and grouping them
是否发酵等等。把它们
all together is as ridiculous as
全部归为一类，就像把
grouping all these snacks together in
所有零食都归为一类一样荒谬，因为
terms of their health
它们对健康的
effects and what we now know is that
影响各不相同。我们现在知道，
some Dairy is actually good for us so
有些乳制品实际上对我们有益，比如
cheese like yogurt and I don't mean this
奶酪和酸奶。我指的不是那种
really kind of heavily sweetened sugary
非常甜的
yogurt I mean like your Greek yogurt
酸奶，而是像希腊酸奶之
shafe those sorts of things you're
类的。 你
playing yogur they've undergone a
吃的酸奶经过了
process called fermentation and that
发酵过程，这会
changes the food Matrix so again we're
改变食物的结构。所以我们又
coming back to that whole importance of
回到了
the structure of the food and by
食物结构的重要性上来，
changing the food Matrix changes how our
食物结构的改变会影响我们
body handles it how our bodies how the
身体对
health effect of their cheese we don't
食物的吸收和处理方式。至于奶酪对健康的影响，我们还没有
fully understand how there's some great
完全了解。
research being undertaken at Reading
雷丁大学正在进行一些很棒的研究，
university really diving into this uh
深入探讨这个问题。
but what we know is if you have cheese
但我们知道的是，适量食用奶酪或
within reason if you have yogurt within
酸奶
reason it does not increase your
不会增加
cholesterol despite being high and
胆固醇，尽管它们
saturated fat now have to caution that
饱和脂肪含量高。需要注意的是，
I'm not saying people should go and have
我并不是说人们应该
you know 300 grams of cheese every day
每天吃300克奶酪，
but within normal kind of intakes of a
而是说在正常摄入量范围内，比如
few portions a day it does not increase
每天吃几份，不会增加
people's cholesterol having cheese or
胆固醇。
the other hand we do know does increase
另一方面，我们知道黄油会增加
your cholesterol now if you're having at
胆固醇。如果你只吃一点点，比如
just putting on a bit of toast I
涂在吐司上，那
wouldn't worry so much but we do know
不用太担心。但我们知道，如果
that if you were to compare cheese
比较奶酪
versus butter which has almost the same
和黄油（它们的脂肪成分几乎相同），黄油会增加胆固醇。
randomized control trials the butter
随机对照试验表明，黄油
will increase your cholesterol but the
会增加胆固醇，但
cheese will not and nuts a lot of people
奶酪不会。很多人
say that nuts cause weight gain no the
说坚果会导致体重增加，但
evidence does not support that so we
证据并不支持这种说法。我们
know
知道，
based on the totality of the evidence do
根据现有证据，食用坚果的人
not gain weight we know this from
不会增重。我们从
epidemiological data I.E people who
流行病学数据中得知，
consume more nuts um tend to quite often
食用更多坚果的人往往体重指数（
have a lower BMI now that could be
BMI）较低。然而，这可能受到以下因素的
confounded by the fact that nut
影响：
consumers and only about 10% in the UK
在英国，只有约10%的人食用坚果，
and even less about 7% in the US even
在美国，这一比例甚至更低，约为7%。而且，坚果
consume USS not consumers tend to have a
消费者通常
healthier overall diet so there is that
整体饮食更健康。因此，存在这种
confounding but clinical trials show
混淆因素。但临床试验表明，
that if you add nuts your diet are
如果在饮食中添加坚果，
included you do not gain weight now that
体重不会增加。这
might be partly because of the
可能部分归因于
mechanisms that we've talked about to do
我们之前讨论过的
with the food Matrix that 20 to 30% of
食物代谢机制，即20%到30%的
the calories are being excreted so the
热量会被排出体外。
backup pack labeling shows that per
包装标签显示每份
portion of n is 170 calories but
坚果含有170卡路里，但
actually on average you only absorb 130
实际上，平均而言，人体只吸收了130
calories so lots of it's coming out it
卡路里，所以大部分热量都被排出了。这
might be because you know they're
可能是因为…… 它们
feeding the microbiome that's helping
滋养着帮助
you know reduce adiposity it's also nuts
你减少脂肪的微生物群，而且它们还具有很强的饱
a satiating so they make you feel more
腹感，让你感觉更
full they also blunt your blood sugar
饱，还能抑制你的血糖
response they have so many other
反应。 它们还有很多其他
benefits that counterbalance any
益处，足以抵消任何
potential for weight game and is there
潜在的体重增加。Nutrabolics 的
anything else on the Nutrabolics list um
清单上还有什么
that is worth highlighting I would say
值得强调的吗？我想说的是，
that I think there's still lots of
我认为人们
confusion around saturated fat okay and
对饱和脂肪和
around cholesterol so cholesterol I went
胆固醇仍然存在很多误解。关于胆固醇，我
and did a blood test and uh the doctor
做了血液检查，医生
said to me that one of my cholesterol
告诉我我的其中一项胆固醇指标
was a little bit on the higher side this
略高，那是
was last year so and think it was the is
去年的事了。我想应该是高密度脂蛋白
it the HDL cholesterol I don't know the
胆固醇（HDL）吧？我不太确定。
way that I experienced it was there's
我理解的是，
this good cholesterol and this bad
胆固醇有好坏之分，
cholesterol and like my bad one was like
我的坏胆固醇有点高，感觉有点
getting a little bit into the region
接近临界值了。医生
where he might have more of a Stern talk
可能会跟我更严肃地谈谈。那是
with me that was last year I think I've
去年的事了，我觉得
done better this year but what is
今年情况好多了。但是
cholesterol and my simplified
胆固醇到底是什么呢？我简单
explanation of it is that is that flawed
解释一下，它有好坏之分吗？
in some way good bad no it's always a
不，它总是更微妙、
more complex um but there are two ways
更复杂一些。我们可以从两个方面来
that we can look at cholesterol we can
看待胆固醇：我们可以从
cholesterol that we eat right and that's
饮食中摄入的胆固醇来看待它，
where I think there's a lot of
我认为这就是关键所在。 关于胆固醇有很多
misinformation and we can look at
误解，我们可以从人体自身产生的
cholesterol in terms of the cholesterol
胆固醇角度来看待它。
that our body produces so our liver is
我们的肝脏会
constantly churning out cholesterol when
不断地产生胆固醇，当
the liver CHS out cholesterol it
肝脏产生胆固醇时，它会将
packages cholesterol into to do two
胆固醇包装成两种
different kind of packages or two
不同的“包裹”或“
different types of parcels and the
小包”。
labeling so to say on these Parcels
这些“包裹”上的标签
determines the health effects of that
决定了胆固醇对健康的影响。
cholesterol so you've got your HDL
所以，我们有高密度脂蛋白
cholesterol which we call our good
胆固醇（HDL），我们称之为“好
cholesterol you've got your LDL
胆固醇”，还有低密度脂蛋白
cholesterol which we call your bad
胆固醇（LDL），我们称之为“坏
cholesterol okay so L is bad yes H is
胆固醇”。L是坏的，H是
good okay they're actually the same in
好的。实际上，就
terms of the cholesterol but it's the
胆固醇本身而言，它们是相同的，但“
label that's on the parcel the label in
包裹”上的标签决定了它们的去向，而标签决定了
terms of which is directing where they
它们的去向。
simple terms LDL is directed um posted
简单来说，LDL会被输送
to your peripheral tissues to your blood
到外周组织和
vessels where it can be taken up and in
血管，在那里它可以被吸收。在
inflammation Ox stress Etc can result in
炎症、氧化应激等特定环境下，LDL会导致动脉粥样硬化，也
atherosclerosis which is that kind of
就是
furring of the arteries uh which over
动脉粥样硬化，随着
time can build up and can lead to you
时间的推移，动脉粥样硬化会不断积累，最终可能导致
know heart attack etc etc okay HDL in
心脏病发作等等。HDL则
very simple terms has a label on it that
非常…… 简单来说，它上面有一个标签，可以
actually enables the reverse cholesterol
促进胆固醇的逆向
transport so actually almost kind of
运输，实际上可以
cleans up some of the cholesterol this
清除一部分胆固醇。这只是
is kind of in very simple terms so if
非常简单的解释，所以如果
any lipidologists are listening they
有脂质学家在听，他们
might be a bit frustrated uh but in very
可能会有点不理解。简单来说，它能把胆固醇运回
to the liver for disposal okay so that's
肝脏进行处理。这就是
why it's considered good what we know is
为什么它被认为是有益的。我们知道，血液中
circulating is really important in terms
低密度脂蛋白胆固醇（LDL-C）的含量
of our cardiovascular disease risk there
对心血管疾病风险非常重要。
are some cholesterol deniers and I know
有些人否认胆固醇的存在，我知道
you've had on your show a cholesterol
你的节目里也请过一位
denier I don't believe in the evidence
否认胆固醇的人。我不相信
he presents I think that the totality of
他提出的证据。我认为所有
the evidence is very very clear that as
证据都非常清楚地表明，随着
your LDL cholesterol increases your risk
LDL-C水平的升高，
of cardiovascular disease your risk of
心血管疾病的风险和
all cause mortality
全因死亡风险都会
increases where there is misinformation
增加。
is around dietary cholesterol that there
关于膳食胆固醇存在误解的地方在于，
was this perception years ago that if
多年前人们认为，如果食用
cholesterol like eggs yeah that it will
像鸡蛋这样富含膳食胆固醇的食物，就会
increase your circulating cholesterol
增加血液中的胆固醇水平，
and therefore increase your risk of
从而增加患
heart disease and therefore there was a
心脏病的风险。因此，
limit years ago put on how many eggs we
多年前曾对鸡蛋的
should eat how much cholesterol we
食用量和胆固醇的摄入量做出过限制。
consume we now know within certain
我们现在知道，在一定的范围内，摄入胆固醇是可以的。
So within the limits that we typically
所以，在我们通常
eat our food containing cholesterol that
摄入的含胆固醇食物的范围内，
dietary cholesterol does not impact our
膳食胆固醇不会影响我们的血液
circula cholesterol obviously at
循环胆固醇水平。当然，
extremes it does but if you're having
极端情况下会有影响。但如果你
one to two eggs a day that's an intake
每天吃一到两个鸡蛋，这个胆固醇摄入量对
negatively for most people impact your
大多数人来说不会对血液
circulating levels of this LDL bad
循环中的低密度脂蛋白（坏
cholesterol if you're having 10 eggs a
胆固醇）水平产生负面影响。如果你每天吃10个鸡蛋，
day then I would be worried okay okay
那我就要担心了。好的，
but yeah cholesterol is another area of
胆固醇是代谢的另一个方面。说到
area of cholesterol heart disease I
胆固醇和心脏病，我
think a really frustrating area of
认为代谢领域一个非常棘手的问题
neutri bolics is saturated
是饱和
fat so we'll talk about saturated fats
脂肪。所以我们来谈谈饱和脂肪，这样
just so I'm I'm super clear on the
我才能更清楚地了解
cholesterol Point what foods have really
胆固醇。哪些食物的
high levels of cholest L the circulating
胆固醇含量很高？血液循环
cholesterol in them okay so you've got
胆固醇又是多少？
dietary cholesterol which is just the
膳食胆固醇就是
cholesterol that's in the food yeah and
食物中的胆固醇，
that has very little impact on
它对血液循环胆固醇的影响很小。
then you have cholesterol that the liver
然后是肝脏
produces and the liver produces that
产生的胆固醇，肝脏
scratch and it's di how diet impacts the
从头开始合成胆固醇。饮食如何影响
liver production that determines how
肝脏的胆固醇生成，决定了
diet impacts our circulating cholesterol
饮食如何影响我们的血液循环胆固醇水平。 胆固醇，
so saturated fat increases the
也就是饱和脂肪，会增加
production of cholesterol by our liver
肝脏产生胆固醇，
and reduces the removal of cholesterol
并减少肝脏清除胆固醇。
by our liver highly refined
高度精制的
carbohydrates can also increase the
碳水化合物也会增加
production of cholesterol by our liver
肝脏产生胆固醇。
so when we're thinking about how diet
所以，当我们考虑饮食如何
impacts our cholesterol particularly our
影响胆固醇，特别是低密度脂蛋白胆固醇（
LDL so our bad cholesterol we don't need
LDL，也就是“坏胆固醇”）时，我们不必
to F worry so much about dietary
太担心
a food Because unless it's extreme it
食物中的胆固醇含量，因为除非含量极高，否则它的
will have a minimal impact we need to
影响微乎其微。我们需要
think about how much saturated fat for
考虑的是我们摄入了多少饱和脂肪，
example we're having because that's one
因为饱和脂肪是影响胆固醇水平的
of the main dietary determents of our
主要饮食因素之一。那么，什么
cholesterol level okay and what is a
是
saturated fat so versus like a normal
饱和脂肪呢？它和普通
fat like is there good and bad fats yes
脂肪有什么区别？脂肪有好坏之分吗？是的，脂肪有
they good and bad fats all of the fats
好坏之分。
that we eat or 98% of the fat that we
我们摄入的脂肪，或者说98%的脂肪，都
eat comes in the form of a molecule
以甘油三酯分子的形式存在。甘油三酯分子由
within it Three fatty acids and it's the
三种脂肪酸组成，正是
mix of these fatty acids that
这些脂肪酸的组合
determine the um Health properties of
决定了甘油三酯的健康特性、
that triglyceride the Melt profile of
熔解曲线
etc and there's lots of different types
等等。脂肪酸有很多不同的种类，
of fatty acids so you're probably
你可能已经很
familiar with amino acids which are
熟悉了。 氨基酸是
types of protein MH and in the way that
蛋白质的一种类型，
amino acids are what make up protein
氨基酸构成蛋白质，脂肪酸
fatty acids are what make up a fat and
构成脂肪，
the quality of that fat and we typically
脂肪的质量也取决于氨基酸的性质。我们通常将脂肪酸
uh separate them into three main classes
分为三大类：
saturated monounsaturated and
饱和脂肪酸、单不饱和脂肪酸和多
polyunsaturated and you might have heard
不饱和脂肪酸。你可能听说
of those terms yeah Loosely yeah and
过这些术语，是的，大致如此。
saturated fatty acids differ in terms of
饱和脂肪酸在生物化学方面有所不同，
their biochemistry and I W bore you with
我再赘述一下。
that um two mono and polyunsaturated
单不饱和脂肪酸和多不饱和脂肪酸
fatty acids they also differ in terms of
在熔点特性方面也不同，也就是
their melt profiles so like how hard
它们的熔点特性。
they are or liquid they are most tend to
大多数饱和脂肪酸倾向于
be hard hence why most hard fats like
较硬，这就是为什么大多数硬质脂肪，比如
butter you know most animal fats which
黄油，
are hard at room temperature tend to be
在室温下较硬的动物脂肪，往往含有
high in saturated fats mono and
大量的饱和脂肪酸。单不饱和脂肪酸和多
polyunsaturated fatty acids differ from
不饱和脂肪酸
saturated fatty acids in terms of their
在生物化学方面与饱和脂肪酸不同，
profile they tend to be liquid
它们的熔点特性更接近液态。
um and polyunsaturated fatty acids are a
多不饱和脂肪酸是一种
very special type of fatty acid because
非常特殊的脂肪酸，因为
they're actually essential for us our
它们对我们来说是必需的，我们的
body can't make them and so they're
身体无法自行合成，所以它们是
essential fatty acids and one of those
必需脂肪酸。其中一种
is
就是
omega-6 which is the fatty acid found in
ω-6脂肪酸，它存在于
sedol which is what people say is why
植物油中，人们常说……
seedor are bad for us which hopefully we
种子对我们有害，希望我们能
debunk there
驳斥这种说法。
and saturated fat as a whole we know is
我们知道饱和脂肪整体上与
cardiovascular disease increased risk of
心血管疾病风险增加、死亡风险增加
or cause mortality
甚至死亡原因有关，
but there's lots of people that say you
但很多人说
know we've got it wrong as nutritional
我们作为营养
scientists we don't know what we're
科学家错了，我们根本不懂。
talking about it because actually
因为实际上，
there's this metaanalysis that showed
有一项荟萃分析表明，
that actually saturated fat isn't bad
饱和脂肪并非
for us and that's because when we think
对我们有害。这是因为当我们
about the health effects of food we have
考虑食物的健康影响时，我们应该
to always think of that instead of
始终考虑食物的益处，而不是其他因素。
what so there was some work that was
一些研究
carried out looking at hundreds and
分析了
hundreds of different clinical trials
数百项不同的临床试验，这些试验
the diet with carbohydrates or trans fat
用碳水化合物、反式脂肪、多
or polyunsaturated fats or mon
不饱和脂肪或单不
unsaturated fats and what this research
饱和脂肪替代了饮食中的饱和脂肪。研究
showed is that if you replace saturated
表明，用全谷物碳水化合物替代饱和脂肪可以改善健康状况；用多不饱和
fats with whole grain
脂肪或
with poly or monounsaturated fats you
单不饱和脂肪替代饱和脂肪也可以改善健康状况；而用
replace saturated fats with refined
精制碳水化合物替代饱和脂肪则
carbohydrates there's no
没有
difference so you could take that study
区别。因此，你可以参考这项研究（
and you could say and this is of
这是
hundreds of different studies and say
数百项不同研究的比较），然后说
saturated fats are really bad for us
饱和脂肪对我们有害。 脂肪对我们真的不好，
because we know that if you replace them
因为我们知道，如果用
with whole grain or poly oron
全谷物或多不
unsaturated fats you have a beneficial
饱和脂肪代替饱和脂肪，就会产生有益的
effect or I could take the same analysis
效果。或者，我也可以用同样的分析
and say oh saturated fats are fine
说，饱和脂肪没问题，
nutritionists have got it all wrong
营养学家们都错了，
because actually there's no detrimental
因为实际上，
effect if you compare it with refined
如果把它和精制碳水化合物相比，它并没有什么有害影响。
about probably about 15 years ago I
大约15年前，当这项荟萃分析发表时，情况正是如此。我
remember looking at the headlines of two
记得当时看过两篇论文的标题，
different papers I won't say what the
我就不说
papers are but one I would say is a
是哪两篇了，但其中一篇的论据更
little bit more evidence-based and one
充分一些，另一篇则是典型的标题党。
they had totally different
它们的标题完全不同：
headlines one said nutrition scientists
一篇说营养科学家都
have got it all wrong we've been lied to
错了，我们被骗了，
saturated fats are fine the other said
饱和脂肪没问题；另一篇说
research again consistently shows
研究再次一致表明
saturated fats are detrimental to our
饱和脂肪对我们的
health obviously that one's
健康有害。显然，前者是对的，
right and they're talking about the same
而且他们讨论的是同一项
study talking about the same study
研究，
because it's the instead of what and
因为关键在于“替代什么”，
that's really important when we think
这在我们
about the health effects the other thing
考虑健康影响时非常重要。另一个让
that does complicate things a little bit
事情变得复杂的因素
of saturated fats is there's lots of
是饱和脂肪……
different types of saturated fats we
饱和脂肪有很多种，我们
know that the type of saturated fat
知道饱和脂肪的种类很
matters but we know the food Matrix that
重要，但我们也知道
it is in that matters and the dairy is a
它所处的食物环境同样重要。乳制品就是一个
great example so you have cheese and
很好的例子。奶酪和
butter exactly the same or almost
黄油的
identical fat composition to entirely
脂肪成分几乎完全相同，但它们
different effects on our cholesterol so
对胆固醇的影响却截然不同。所以，不能
it is a little bit more Nuance than
简单地
saying all saturated fats bad it depends
说所有饱和脂肪都不好，这取决于饱和脂肪的
on the type and the food it's in and
种类、它所处的食物环境，以及
what types of food have um saturated
哪些食物中的饱和
fats that have
脂肪来自
a less than healthy food Matrix so I
不太健康的食物环境。因此，我
would say the type of saturated fats
认为
that we want to avoid are the saturated
我们应该避免的是
fats that are found in most animal
大多数动物产品中含有的饱和脂肪，
products except fermented dairy except
除了发酵乳制品（
cheese except yogurt so beef
奶酪和酸奶除外）。比如牛油，
Tallow I would say the evidence
证据
consistently shows is not favorable for
一致表明它对
our health lard mhm butter in large
我们的健康不利。猪油，嗯，大量食用黄油也不利。还有
amounts um you know and then the meat
肉类中固有的脂肪，比如
the meat takes salami you can see the
萨拉米香肠，你可以看到
fat in there take steak for example you
里面的脂肪。再比如牛排，你可以
know cut off the visible bits of the fat
切掉肉眼可见的脂肪部分。
it's okay in small amounts I'm not
少量食用是可以的，我并不是
saying we should avoid it
说我们应该
totally but if you have the option of
完全避免。 但如果可以选择
kind of cutting off trimming the fat
减少脂肪摄入，
then I would and then there are some
我会这么做。有些
tropical oils that are very high in
热带植物油饱和脂肪含量很高，
saturated fat palm oil for example
比如
coconut oil although the JW is out on
棕榈油和椰子油。虽然耶和华见证人对
the health effects of coconut oil but
椰子油的健康影响持保留意见，但
palmo for example is very high in
棕榈油饱和脂肪含量很高，
saturated fat we know it increases our
我们知道它会升高
cholesterol if you had to give me some
胆固醇。如果让你根据我们今天讨论的所有内容给我一些
principles for eating based on
饮食原则，就像
like and I and I had to force you to
我之前强迫你给出的
just give me five principles for eating
五个原则一样，你会给出哪
be five
五个？
okay I would say first and foremost find
首先，也是最重要的，找到
food or dietry pattern that you
你
enjoy that brings you pleasure cookies
喜欢的、能给你带来愉悦感的食物或饮食模式。
okay but we are not these aren't
好的，但这些并不互相排斥。好的，好的，
okay fine that brings me
能给我带来
pleasure okay that's really important
愉悦感的食物或饮食模式非常重要。这些并不互相排斥。所以，找到一种能给
dietary pattern that brings you
你带来愉悦感的饮食模式，
because because food is there to be
因为食物是用来
enjoyed and it will be a sustainable
享受的，而且这种
dietary pattern and because we know that
饮食模式是可持续的。我们知道，饮食的
consistency and sustainability is really
规律性和可持续性非常
important in how you eat
重要。
okay second I would say think about how
其次，我想说的是，想想你是怎么
eat think about how fast you're eating
吃的，想想你吃得有多快，
slow down chew more chew more don't eat
放慢速度，多咀嚼，多咀嚼，不要
late at
在
night try and eat within a 10 or 12 hour
深夜吃东西，尽量在一天之内吃完。  10到12小时的
eating window and just on this t point
进食窗口，就在这时，在
you were before we started recording you
我们开始录音之前，
you were saying that you wouldn't mind
你说
if I chewed some nuts and spat them out
如果我嚼一些坚果然后吐出来，
so you could look look at them um why
你可以看看，你不介意。嗯，为什么
does chewing more have a impact again
咀嚼次数越多会有影响呢？为了确保
just so I can I'm clear
我理解正确，我再解释一下。
so chewing uh can impact how you break
咀嚼会影响食物的分解方式，是的，很明显。
the food down yeah obviously uh but we
但我们也
also know chewing impacts your hunger
知道，咀嚼会影响你的饥饿感
and your fullness signals so there's
和饱腹感信号。
some evidence to show if you chew your
一些证据表明，如果你咀嚼
food 40 times versus 15 times it can
食物40次和15次，
food makes you feel okay so the chewing
食物带给你的饱腹感会有所不同。所以，咀嚼
effect is sending some kind of signal
会向大脑发送某种信号。是的，是的，是的。
yep yep to my brain yep again this isn't
这
an area that I I have expertise in but
方面我不是专家，但
that's what the evidence is showing so
证据表明确实如此。除了
as well as your gut sending signals to
肠道会向
your brain receptors on your gut saying
大脑的受体发送信号，告诉大脑你
whether you're full there's something
是否饱腹之外，
going on when you're chewing your food
咀嚼食物时也会发生一些事情，
as well that's important okay um and
这很重要。
chewing your food also changes the rate
咀嚼食物还会改变消化速度，
therefore at which you're eating so it
从而影响…… 你吃东西，所以
changes your eating speed ah okay makes
你的进食速度会改变，啊，好的，有道理。
sense so on that second Point I've got
关于第二点，我还有
slow down two more don't eat late at
两点要说：放慢速度，不要在
night and eat within a 10 to 12 hour
深夜吃东西，并在10到12小时的进食窗口内进食。
third would be Go Back to Basics yep
第三点是回归基本，是的，摄入
have a good amount of fiber have a good
足够的纤维，摄入
amount of healthy oils that's your olive
足够的健康油脂，比如
oils in your olive oil D I say it seed
橄榄油。我通常说是
oils but olive oil I would say is the
植物油，但橄榄油可以说是
king and queen of the oils
油中之王。还有，要保持
and you know have that balanced plate
膳食均衡，
rather than obsessing over a single
而不是执着于单一
food okay number
食物。好的，
four don't think of food in isolation
第四点，不要孤立地看待食物。
Okay think about your diet in relation
想想你的饮食与
to or alongside your sleep your stress
睡眠、压力和
your physical
身体
activity and number five can you remind
活动之间的关系。第五点，你能提醒
me of what I've I've done yes so I'm 48
我一下我之前说过什么吗？好的。我48岁了，正处于
I'm in the depth of per menopause I'm
更年期，我是
one of those like 90% of people that
那90%
have brain fog and memory loss so number
有脑雾和记忆力减退症状的人之一。所以第一点
one uh was food that brings you pleasure
是选择能给你带来愉悦感、
which is sustainable and allows you to
可持续且能让你坚持
be consistent number two is really
下去的食物。第二点是认真
thinking about how you eat so slowing
思考。 关于你的饮食方式，比如放慢速度，
down chewing more not eating late at
多咀嚼，不要
night and trying to have a a a shorter
深夜进食，尽量缩短
eating window of 10 to 12 hours number
进食窗口，控制在10到12小时。
three was Go Back to Basics which is
第三点是回归基础，也就是多吃
high fiber whole grains fruits healthy
高纤维的全谷物、水果、健康的
oils and overall just a balanced play
油脂，总之就是均衡饮食。
and number four is don't think of your
第四点是不要
nutrition in isolation so think of it in
孤立地看待营养，要结合
the context of your exercise your sleep
你的运动、睡眠
and all of these other lifestyle factors
以及其他生活方式因素来考虑。
and number five don't deny
第五点是不要完全拒绝
yourself anything think think about what
自​​己，想想
you can add in rather than what you take
可以增加什么，而
away don't deny yourself anything so
不是减少什么。偶尔吃点
cookies are still on the
饼干也无妨。
yes you mentioned the
是的，你提到了更年期，你
um per menopause you said you're in per
说你
menopause currently how does that factor
目前正处于更年期，这
and what is the because I've got this
和我们今天讨论的所有内容有什么关系？因为我
graph here that I'd found um about the
这里有一张关于
menopause transition which talks about
更年期过渡的图表，它描述了
happening inside the body you've
身体内部发生的各种变化，你
probably seen this quite a few times
可能以前看过很多次了，
before which I'll put on the screen and
我会把它显示在屏幕上，并在
link below for anybody but what is the
下方提供链接。但是
relationship between my diet and my
我的饮食和我的更年期之间有什么关系？有什么需要
be aware of there is I mean that you
注意的吗？ 我的意思是，你
know the menopause has a huge impact on
知道更年期对
how we respond to food it has a huge
我们对待食物的方式有着巨大的影响，它对
of Health that we've talked about our
我们之前讨论过的所有健康支柱——
sleep our stress our physical activity
睡眠、压力、运动
you know and diet and I think it's
和饮食——都有着巨大的影响。我认为
something we're talking about a lot more
我们现在更多地谈论更年期，
now and we should be talking about it a
而且我们也应该更多地谈论它。
lot more now you know 50% of the
你知道，50%的
population at some point are going to go
人口会在某个阶段经历
through the menopause and it's a
更年期，这是一个
transitional period of great disturbance
充满干扰、令人不安的过渡期，给
many women and we've conducted lots of
许多女性带来了沉重的负担。我们
research uh at Z on the menopause and
在Z公司对更年期进行了大量研究，
what we know is that prior to uh the
我们发现，在
menopause which is basically the point
更年期之前（基本上是指
one year after your last menstrual cycle
最后一次月经周期后一年），女性会经历一个更年期过渡期，在这个过渡
period where your estrogen and other
期中，雌激素和其他
hormones are fluctuating dayto day so
激素水平每天都在波动，就像坐
it's like this roller coaster which I
过山车一样，我
think your graph shows really nicely
认为你的图表很好地展示了这一点。激素水平就像坐过山车一样波动。
and so what's happening is is your
所以，正在发生的事情是，雌
estrogen isn't just slowly declining as
激素水平并不会随着时间推移而缓慢下降。
you reach per menopause so that
更年期前期，
menopause but you're on this roller
也就是绝经前的过渡期，雌激素水平会像坐过山车一样波动。
menopause but you're still in that point
绝经后，雌激素水平会趋于稳定，但仍然处于雌
where you're having less estrogen so
激素水平较低的阶段。雌激素这种
less of the hormone that we know has
激素对身体有着
such wide reaching effects and the
广泛的影响。
reason that the per menopause transition
更年期前期
as well as postmenopause period in a
和绝经后期之所以对
women's life is so important is because
女性如此重要，是因为雌
estrogen the hormone that fluctuates
激素——这种在
during the per menopause and then
更年期前期波动，然后
reduces and declines in
在绝经后期减少的激素——
body nearly every cell in our body has
对我们身体的几乎每个细胞都有
estrogen receptors so our brain um our
雌激素受体，包括大脑、
blood vessels nearly everywhere so this
血管等等。因此，
per menopausal phase and also the
更年期前期雌激素水平的波动以及绝经
reduction postmenopausally has
后期的减少会对
uh health effects so for example
健康产生深远的影响。例如，
postmenopausally women are five times
绝经后女性
greater risk of having a heart attack
患心脏病的风险是正常女性的五倍。这部分
now some of that's due to age but it's
是由于年龄增长，但也与
also due to the loss in estrogen women
雌激素水平下降有关。此外，女性
are five times more likely to have
患
abdominal obesity which is fat around
腹部肥胖（即腹部脂肪堆积）的可能性也是正常女性的五倍。
the tummy and that's because of
腹部周围的脂肪堆积是因为雌
estrogen's role in uh fat tissue
激素在脂肪组织沉积中的作用。
deposited we see in our own Zer predict
根据我们自己的Zer predict
research Prem menopause women are doing
研究，绝经前女性
well compared to men in terms of many of
在许多
these what we call intermediary risk
我们称之为
factors of cardiovascular disease blood
心血管疾病中间风险因素（如
pressure cholesterol glucose insulin Etc
血压、胆固醇、葡萄糖、胰岛素等）方面，与男性相比表现良好。然而，
as soon as they hit the menopause
一旦她们进入绝经期，这些风险因素就会
suddenly they catch up with men and it
突然赶上男性，甚至
gets worse and so suddenly their blood
恶化。她们的
pressure is higher than men or their
血压会突然高于男性，或者
cholesterol is the same level as men so
胆固醇水平与男性相同。
we see this as well in our zoedic
我们在Zoedic的研究中也观察到，
research that postmenopausally and per
绝经后和绝经前
menopausal people's cholesterol and
女性的胆固醇，尤其是低密度脂蛋白
cholesterol increases by 25% and this is
胆固醇（坏胆固醇），会增加25%。这都与雌
estrogen has in our body we also see the
激素在我们体内广泛的作用有关。我们还观察到
estrogen impacts and therefore the per
雌激素对
menopause and postmenopause how we
我们绝经前和绝经后
metabolize food so we see bigger
食物代谢的影响。因此，我们看到绝经后女性的
excursions in postmill glucose and
血糖和脂肪水平波动更大。
it's all linked to the role that
这同样与
estrogen plays uh in our metabolism and
雌激素在我们体内的作用有关。
aware of regarding the per menopause and
关于更年期前和
postmenopause phase is is the symptoms
更年期后阶段，我认为最重要的是了解
that women
女性
experience
经历的症状。
and we've done some research in 70,000
我们对7万名受试者进行了一项研究，
individuals where we've looked at how
调查了
prevalent these symptoms are we see that
这些症状的普遍程度。研究发现，
99% of per menopause or women experience
99%的更年期前或更年期女性
at least one menopausal symptom we see
至少经历一种更年期症状，
that 66% of per menopausal women have 12
66%的更年期前女性有12种或
more and this has a huge burden we know
更多症状。这给她们带来了巨大的负担。我们
from other surveys 10% of women leave
从其他调查中得知，10%的女性
the workforce during the per menopause
在更年期前
and post-menopausal phase because of the
和更年期后阶段会因为
burden that these symptoms have on their
这些症状对
quality of life and what age does this
生活质量的影响而离开职场。那么，这些症状通常发生在什么年龄段呢？
symptoms so uh typically people become
通常情况下，人们在51岁时进入
menopausal as in postmenopausal stop
更年期，也就是绝经后，
their menstrual cycles at 51 the
月经周期停止。
menopausal transition period can be
更年期过渡期可能
anything from 2 to 10 years typically
持续2到10年。通常情况下，
47 many women start to experience p
许多女性在47岁左右开始经历
menopausal uh symptoms and these include
更年期症状，这些症状包括： 更年期
symptoms like brain fog anxiety memory
症状包括脑雾、焦虑、记忆力
loss irritability low libido change in
减退、易怒、性欲低下、
metabolism um and now I'm in that PO
新陈代谢改变等等。我现在正处于更年期前期，
of the others but there's about 50
其他症状我都忘了，但
symptoms that are recognized and we see
已知的更年期症状大约有50种。我们
in our own research that the amount of
自己的研究表明，
women experiencing symptoms is really
出现这些症状的女性比例非常
high so we see that 85% of women are
高，85%的女性
saying they have brain fog they have
表示她们有脑雾、
anxiety they have memory loss it it's
焦虑和记忆力减退等症状。
experiencing these
出现这些
symptoms and what's really interesting
症状的女性比例真的很高。有趣的
is we know yes HRT so hormone
是，我们知道激素
replacement therapy therapy or MHT um uh
替代疗法（HRT）或激素替代疗法（MHT）
can help reduce many of these symptoms
可以帮助减轻许多这些症状，
but we also know that diet can help as
但我们也知道饮食也有帮助。
well and I think actually see one of the
我认为，我们关于
research looking at menopause and
更年期及其
symptoms is that typically when we think
症状的研究中，最有趣的发现之一是，通常当我们想到
of menopausal symptoms we think about
更年期时，我们往往会想到…… 说到更年期症状，我们首先想到的就是
hot flushes mhm and if I was to ask you
潮热，嗯……如果我问你，
actually I wished I'd have asked you
其实我应该在
before I said that but if I was to ask
说这话之前就问
you to if you were to think of a
你，如果你要说一个
menopause symptom what would come to
更年期症状，你
your mind first I would say hot flushes
首先想到的是什么？我会说是潮热，
because that seems to be um the only
因为在我看来，人们似乎只有在
is when they're talking about menopause
谈论更年期的时候才会提到潮热。
in my world and then I'd say brain fog
然后我会说是脑雾，是的。
yep and what's really interesting is hot
真正有趣的是，
flushers are the one of the least common
潮热是最不常见的
symptoms about 40% of women in our
症状之一。在我们的研究中，大约40%的女性
research have hot flushes 85% have uh
有潮热症状，85%的女性有
brain fog 85% have all of the other
脑雾症状，85%的女性有其他所有与
brain related um uh
大脑相关的
symptoms and yet typically we always
症状。然而，我们通常总是
think about hot flushes and this is
想到潮热，这是
because there just hasn't been loads of
因为
research on menopause and so I think
关于更年期的研究并不多。所以我认为
what's really exciting is there is now a
真正令人兴奋的是，现在
lot more research on menopause so I
关于更年期的研究越来越多，所以我
think the future is really exciting but
认为未来非常令人期待。但
I think what comes with this is yet more
我认为随之而来的，是更多的
neutrols MH and that's because I think
神经系统疾病和更年期症状。 那是因为我认为现在存在一个
there's this whole area of what we call
我们称之为“
menow washing I don't have you heard of
更年期洗白”的领域。我没听说过“
menow i't stick menow for menopause in
更年期”这个词，我不会在
front of any product you can charge 10
任何产品前面加上“更年期”之类的字眼，然后就把价格抬高
times as much I could call this a
十倍。我可以把这叫做“
menopause tea it's actually Yorkshire
更年期茶”，它其实是约克郡
Tea and it's a very good cup of tea I
红茶，而且味道很好。我
could call this meno tea and charge 10
可以把它叫做“更年期茶”，然后把
times as much for that tea bag without
这个茶包的价格抬高十倍，而没有
any evidence because women are desperate
任何证据支持，因为女性现在很绝望。45
45% of women say their symptoms are so
%的女性表示她们的症状非常
burdensome they'll try anything 10%
严重，她们会尝试任何方法。10%的女性
leaving the workforce because of their
因为这些症状而离开了职场。
symptoms and so we have to be really
所以我们必须非常
careful that we are only selling
谨慎，只销售有
evidence-based supplements for which
科学依据的补充剂，而
there isn't much evidence at the
目前针对这类补充剂的证据还不够充分。
moment and I think that the evidence
我认为，
way forward for now alongside for those
目前最好的方法是，通过整体上更健康的饮食模式来减轻症状，同时对于那些
who choose to hormone replacement
选择激素替代
therapy a recent survey showed that 30%
疗法的人来说，最近的一项调查显示，30%
of menopause women are trying herbal REM
的更年期女性正在尝试草药
remedies 30% are trying vitamins and 51%
疗法，30%正在尝试维生素，51%
are trying any kind of dietary therapy
正在尝试各种饮食疗法
as an alternative to HRT that was in I
作为激素替代疗法的替代方案。 在
news which kind of supports what you're
新闻报道中，这似乎也印证了你的说法，
saying that there's lots of people
很多人都在
searching for because I think from the
搜索相关信息。因为就
experiences that I've had with people
我与那些
talking to me about menopause it seems
谈论更年期的人的交流来看，这似乎
to be an incredibly confusing period of
是一个极其令人困惑的时期，
life where you can't make sense of
你无法理解正在
what's happening and all the old rules
发生的一切，所有那些老生常谈的
of just you know hit the gym and eat a
健身和
bit healthier seem to go out the window
健康饮食之类的建议似乎都失效了，
because there's something deeper at play
因为
in your body so it's not that you're not
你的身体内部发生了更深层次的变化。这并不是说你吃得不对，也不是说
eating right or it's not that you're not
你
sleeping right it's a deeper hormonal
睡得不好，而是出现了一种你从未经历过的、更深层次的激素
fluctuation that you've actually never
波动。
experienced before so of course you're
所以，你当然会感到
going to be really confused and um quite
非常困惑，而且，
easily uh gas lit as well I imagine
我想你也很容易被误导。
because you know I've had someone say to
因为，我曾听人说过，
me that they felt like they were going
她们感觉自己快要
crazy and then people started thinking
疯了，然后人们就开始觉得
they were just like kind of going crazy
她们只是有点精神失常而已。是的，
fortunately I think it's changing yeah
幸运的是，我认为这种情况正在改变。
but historically we didn't talk about it
但是，在过去，我们很少谈论更年期。
you know I vaguely remember my mom
我隐约记得我妈妈
saying I'm really hot I'm having hot
说过：“我好热啊，我……”
flush but we didn't talk about menopause
潮热，但我们不谈论更年期，
we didn't talk about periods we just
不谈论月经，就是
didn't talk about it in that you know
不谈论这些。你知道，在
when I was growing up and unfortunately
我成长的过程中，很遗憾，
my mother's no longer alive so I don't
我的母亲已经去世了，所以我不太
really know what she did go through and
了解她经历了什么。
I want to talk about it people are
我想谈谈这个话题，现在人们开始
talking about it we have people like
谈论它了。像
deina MCO who are amazing because
迪娜·MCO这样的人很棒，因为
they're getting women talking about it
她们让女性谈论更年期，
so we're no longer ashamed so I think
所以我们不再感到羞耻。我认为
the tide is really turning
风向正在转变。
but menopause is this perfect storm
但更年期就像一场完美的风暴，
because you have these burdensome
因为你不仅要忍受这些令人痛苦的
symptoms and then you have alongside it
症状，还要面对我刚才
is these health effects that I talked
提到的那些健康问题，而我认为我们谈论得还不够。比如，
about so women going for the menopause
女性在更年期睡眠很差。说实话，
aren't sleeping I mean my sleep is all
我的睡眠也完全紊乱。
good night's sleep Stephen I feel like
斯蒂芬，如果我能睡个好觉，我感觉自己就像
superwoman it it I'm almost it reminds
超人一样。这让
me the state I'm in at the moment is
我想起我现在的状态，就像
like how I was when I had kids where you
我生孩子的时候一样，你
know I'm getting four or five hours
知道，我只能睡四五个小时，
sleep then I wake up if I'm lucky I
然后醒来，如果幸运的话，也许还能再睡一会儿。
might get back to sleep so you've got
所以，
women they're not getting enough sleep
女性…… 她们睡眠不足，很多
you've got women who often are feeling a
女性常常感到
bit depressed or anxious or you know
抑郁、焦虑，或者因为思维
brain fog because of their memory loss
迟钝、记忆力减退而失去自信。
anxiety you've got the hormones changing
激素变化导致
your body composition suddenly you're
身体成分改变，虽然
eating and doing everything the
饮食和活动都和以前
same but all the fats being directed to
一样，但脂肪却都堆积在
your tummy your hunger signals are
腹部，饥饿信号也变得异常敏感，对
different food changes and we see this
不同食物的渴望也随之改变。
again in our own research that
我们的研究再次证实，
postmenopause women tend to eat a lot
绝经后女性
more sugary Foods than Prem menopause so
比绝经前女性摄入更多含糖食物。各种因素叠加在一起，形成了一种“
you've got this perfect storm of things
完美风暴”。与此同时，你真的想
really want to do some physical activity
进行体育锻炼吗？
are you really motivated to start eating
你真的有动力开始
healthier and you know when you're
健康饮食吗？当你
exhausted and it goes back again to that
精疲力竭时，这一切都再次凸显了
importance of sleep and that interaction
睡眠的重要性，以及
of sleep with our food choices and how
睡眠与食物选择和
we respond to food there's so many
我们对食物的反应之间的相互作用。有很多
things to think and I think it's really
事情需要考虑，我认为
tough in that Perry and postmenopausal
在绝经前和绝经后
phase when your body's changing when
阶段，身体发生变化，
you're tired when you're feeling a bit
疲惫不堪，感觉糟糕透顶，
rubbish to also take control of your
要控制自己的饮食真的非常困难。 你的
diet but it's the most important time
饮食固然重要，但这却是最关键的时期，
because it's when your cholesterol
因为此时你的胆固醇会
increases it's when your blood pressure
升高，血压也会
increases it's when all of this fat
升高，
tissue around your belly is releasing
腹部周围的脂肪组织会释放
harmful inflammatory chemicals Etc so
有害的炎症化学物质等等。所以，
it's when unfortunately we really do
不幸的是，我们真的
need to take stock of our physical
需要好好审视一下我们的
activity of what we're eating and our
运动量、饮食和
stress levels m but it's probably one of
压力水平。但同时，这可能是
the most challenging times to do it as
最难做到这些的时期之一。
well you must be incredibly stressed
你肯定
through that period but also just
在那段时间承受着巨大的压力，而且，
thinking about your relationships if you
如果
if you're in a relationship in a
你正处于一段
heterosexual marriage with a with a
异性婚姻关系中，你的
husband who isn't going through that at
丈夫可能并没有经历更年期，
that period of their life and you said
那么你还要考虑你的人际关系。你提到
there was a libido
性欲
um issue that's symptomatic of menopause
问题，这也是更年期的症状之一。要
as well to navigate all of that and for
应对所有这些，还要让
the people around you to understand
周围的人理解
what's going on in your head must be
你内心的感受，这肯定
incredibly stressful incredibly
压力巨大，真的非常巨大。
stressful I'm I
我
like I'm very um I feel very I don't
非常……我不
know what the right words are here but I
知道该用什么词来形容，但我
feel very um
非常……
sympathetic because I can't imagine I
感同身受，因为我无法想象……我
don't think there's a point in the man's
觉得这毫无意义。 男人的
life where we go through such a profound
一生中，我们的荷尔蒙会经历如此深刻的
change in our um hormones in such a
变化，而且这种变化来得如此突然，令人困惑。所以
so it's like but I think Stephen if we
我觉得，斯蒂芬，如果我们能
raise awareness so that men are aware
提高男性对性欲低下的认识，让他们了解这一点，就能更好地
and they can support their partners and
支持他们的伴侣。
example we see in our own research
比如，我们自己的研究表明，
whilst it might not be the most common
虽然性欲低下可能不是最常见的症状，但
women rate it as the most burdensome
女性却认为它是最令人困扰的。
really so we monitor not just the
因此，我们不仅监测
prevalence so how common the symptoms
症状的普遍程度，还会
are we also ask people how much impacts
询问人们这些症状对她们生活质量的影响程度。更年期
postmenopausal women rate that as their
前后的女性普遍认为，
that causes my lowering of libido I'm
性欲低下是她们生活中负担最重的症状。因为如果我睡眠不足，感觉不到性欲，我就不会想做爱。这跟我的荷尔蒙水平是否受到化学物质的影响导致性欲下降无关。
sleep I want to go to sleep yeah exactly
我只想睡觉，不想做爱。没错，
so even if you know and especially I
即使你感觉不好，
don't feel good I don't feel sexy I'm
感觉不到性欲，我的
probably my mood might be altered and
情绪也可能受到影响。
yeah you're tummy suddenly grow yeah
你的肚子突然变大了，是的，
it's not going to be so what do what
这不会是正常的。那么，
advice do you give to those the women
你会给那些
been going through that you said that
正在经历同样情况的女性什么建议呢？你之前说过
you're on hormone replacement therapy
你自己也在接受激素替代疗法，
yourself previously um and that's had a
嗯，
I guess a positive impact on your
我想这对你的更年期历程产生了积极的影响。
menopause Journey yes I still sleep
是的，我仍然睡得
really badly yeah um I don't think HRT
很差。嗯，我不认为激素替代疗法
is the answer for everyone and some
适合所有人，有些
people can't take it if they're
人如果存在
contraindicated with certain risk
与
related to cancer um and some people
癌症相关的禁忌症就不能服用，嗯，有些人
choose not to take it and it certainly
选择不服用，而且它当然
doesn't solve everything uh I do think
不能解决所有问题。嗯，我确实认为有
the evidence is very compelling for
非常令人信服的证据表明，它可以
reduction in many Sy sys I think the
减轻许多症状，我认为证据很有
compelling um or increasing and building
说服力，或者说，越来越多的证据表明，
for the beneficial effects it also has
它对更年期的
on some of these health effects that
一些健康问题也有益处，
happen during menopause like blood
比如
pressure cholesterol uh tummy fat so
血压、胆固醇、腹部脂肪等等。所以
I've chosen to take it for both health
我选择服用它，既是为了健康，
and for symptoms but there's reasonable
也是为了缓解症状。但现在也有合理的
evidence now showing that diet can help
证据表明，饮食可以帮助
reduce symptoms there isn't a one siiz
减轻症状。没有一劳永逸的办法，没有
fix it's all there isn't a silver bullet
灵丹妙药，
but an overall healthier dietary pattern
但我相信，更健康的饮食模式
I believe can reduce menopause symptoms
可以减轻症状。 关于更年期症状，
this comes from other published research
这方面的研究结果来自其他已发表的研究
as well as our own research that we've
以及我们Zoi公司自身的研究。
done at zoi where we've looked in a
在Zoi，我们对
subgroup of individuals over 12 to 18
一部分人群进行了为期12至18
week period and looked at those who
周的观察，重点关注那些
transition to a healthier diet they're
过渡到更健康饮食的人群。他们
actually following The Zo program but
实际上遵循的是Zoi的饮食计划，但其
the underlying principles are the same
基本原则
for all individuals to follow a healthy
对所有人群都适用：
diet so increase plant diversity
增加植物性食物的多样性，
increase fiber a very kind of
增加膳食纤维，类似于
Mediterranean style diet and what we see
地中海式饮食。我们发现，
in those people who are improving their
改善
diet they have a 35% reduction in
饮食的人群症状减轻了35%，这是一个非常显
symptoms now that's huge I do have to
著的改善。不过，我必须指出，这项研究
wasn't a control arm so it's not a
没有设置对照组，因此它并非
clinical an rcts we call it it's a a a
我们所说的随机对照试验（RCT）。这只是一项
study where we followed people at one
研究，我们在某个时间点追踪了受试者，
point in time and collected data another
并在另一个时间点收集了数据。
point in time what we now need to do is
我们现在需要做的是，
repeat this with a control arm to see if
通过设置对照组来重复这项研究，看看是否能
we see the same size effect but there
观察到同样显著的效果。
are other studies that have in a
其他一些研究也进行了
randomized control trial asked people to
随机对照试验，让受试者分别
follow the Mediterranean diet or control
遵循地中海式饮食或对照
diet and they see a similar magnitude of
饮食，结果发现
around 30% reduction in symptoms which
症状减轻幅度也达到了30%左右，这
is huge and promising I think but I
是一个非常显著且令人鼓舞的结果。
think where we have to be really careful
我们必须非常谨慎地
with menopause because we are desperate
对待更年期，因为我们感到绝望，
because we're struggling I think we're
因为我们正在经历痛苦。我认为我们
really susceptible to marketing to this
很容易受到更年期营销的影响，
many supplements that are being sold as
很多保健品都被宣传成“
the Silver Bullet you know and I see it
灵丹妙药”，我
on social media and I think firstly okay
在社交媒体上经常看到。首先，
if it works for you great if you can
如果它对你有效，那很好；如果你
afford it great but what worries me is
负担得起，那就更好了。但我担心的是，
people who are spending a lot of money
人们把原本
that they could be using for a healthy
可以用于健康
dietary pattern or you know a gym
饮食、健身房
membership or whatever on a supplement
会员或其他方面的钱花在了保健品上，而这些保健品并
that there is no evidence of support and
没有证据支持，而且
the evidence is very very weak except
证据非常薄弱。除了
for a supplement called soy eyes of
大豆
flavones there is very weak evidence
异黄酮之外，
that any other supplements will work
其他保健品的效果都很难保证。
isoflavones yeah so soy isoflavones are
大豆异黄酮是
a particular chemical that are found in
一种存在于某些食物中的特殊化学物质，
some foods it's a chemical that has a
它的
structure very similar to estrogen so
结构与雌激素非常相似，可以与
in the body which is why it has a
体内的雌激素受体结合，因此
beneficial effects on many symptoms now
对许多症状有益。
small amounts in the UK and the us we
在英国，人们食用大豆异黄酮的量相当少。 我们
day on average in the Far East like
平均每天摄入的维生素D可能只有1毫克左右，而像
China they consume about 70 milligrams a
中国这样的远东地区的人们，由于日常饮食，每天摄入的维生素D大约有70毫克。
day as part of the natural diet so in
因此，在
those kind of countries they actually
这些国家，
menopause symptoms compared to us they
更年期症状的发生率实际上比我们低得多。虽然她们也会
still have menopause symptoms but it's a
有更年期症状，但程度要
bit lower than
轻一些。
us what we know is that if you
我们知道，如果给
the vast majority of people but not
大多数人（但并非
everyone it will reduce symptoms a
所有人）补充大豆油，可以稍微减轻症状，虽然
little bit not totally but it can reduce
不能完全消除，但确实可以减轻
symptoms and is your underlying how
症状。那么，你的潜在
Health a predictive factor of the amount
健康状况是否会影响
of symptoms you'll experience if I was
你经历的症状数量呢？
if I'm obese and then I go into per
如果我肥胖，然后进入
menopause are my symptoms going to be
更年期，我的症状会
more
更
significant so that's a good question
严重吗？这是一个很好的问题。
we've looked at how living with obesity
我们已经研究了肥胖如何
can impact your symptoms and we do see
影响症状，我们发现，
that if you're living with obesity you
如果你肥胖，你的症状发生率会
have a higher prevalent uh number of
更高。
symptoms okay we see that if you have an
我们还发现，如果你一
unhealthy diet to start with you have a
开始就有不健康的饮食习惯，你的症状也会
higher number of symptoms we see that if
更多。此外，如果你
you have low physical activity you smoke
缺乏运动、吸烟
Etc yes it's associated with higher
等等，这些因素都与更年期症状有关。是的，这些都与更年期症状有关。 虽然
symptoms this is all Association data
症状较重，但这些数据都只是关联性数据，
though it doesn't show causality and
并不代表因果关系。非常
it's really important to say that for
重要的一点是，
quite a while I ignored my gut I ignored
我曾经很长一段时间都忽略了我的肠道健康，忽略了
the role it plays when it comes to my
它对我
overall health and it wasn't until the
整体健康的影响。直到
team from Zoe came onto my podcast that
Zoe团队做客我的播客节目，
I realized I couldn't ignore it anymore
我才意识到我不能再忽视它了。Tim
Spectre and Professor Sarah Berry that I
Spectre教授和Sarah Berry教授给我留下了深刻的印象，
ended up investing in Zoe and they're
最终我投资了Zoe，他们
now a sponsor of this podcast they help
现在是本播客的赞助商。他们帮助
me to view my gut as the gateway to
我将肠道视为通往
Better Health that when in balance my
更健康生活的门户，当
microbiome could strengthen my immunity
肠道菌群平衡时，可以增强我的免疫力、
elevate my mood and fight off disease
改善我的情绪并抵抗疾病，
which I now know to be true I trust zoee
我现在确信这是真的。我信任Zoe，
because they have one of the largest
因为他们拥有
microbiome databases in the world and
世界上最大的微生物组数据库之一。
when you sign up you'll get one of the
注册后，您将获得全球
most scientifically Advanced atome test
最先进的微生物组测试
kits on the planet and a personalized
套件之一，以及一份个性化的
nutrition program to help you make
营养计划，帮助您做出更
smarter food choices and because you're
明智的食物选择。作为
one of my listeners use code Steven 10
我的听众，使用优惠码Steven 10即可享受
for 10% off your membership head to
会员费10%的折扣。访问
zoe.com
zoe.com了解更多信息。
now we take our time when it comes to
现在，我们在
hiring at flight story because I
招聘方面会非常谨慎。 之所以选择这个话题，是因为我
fundamentally believe the success of a
坚信企业的成功与
you are at hiring and better hiring
招聘能力息息相关，而更高效的招聘
starts with smarter insights LinkedIn
始于更敏锐的洞察力。LinkedIn
who's a sponsor of this podcast has some
是本播客的赞助商，拥有业内
of the strongest hiring data available
最强大的招聘数据，可以
to help you identify the best candidates
帮助您找到最适合您
for your business their platform will
企业的候选人。他们的平台
even pair you with those who match what
甚至会将您与那些符合您需求的人进行匹配，这些需求
you're looking for which might lie
可能超出
outside of the job description and More
职位描述，体现在
in their unique skills and interests
他们独特的技能和兴趣上。
because these days hiring isn't just
因为如今，招聘不仅仅是
about finding the most qualified person
找到最合格的人，
but also finding the one whose
还要找到
experience abilities and interests align
经验、能力和兴趣
with your company's Mission and it goes
与公司使命相契合的人。而且，招聘的范围
beyond candidates who are applying for
远不止于那些正在申请
jobs too in any given week 171 million
工作的候选人。每周都有1.71亿LinkedIn
members who aren't actively seeking jobs
会员虽然没有积极寻找工作，但他们仍然
are open to New Opportunities find your
对新的机会持开放态度。
next great hire on LinkedIn and start
在LinkedIn上找到您下一个优秀的员工，
today by posting your job for free just
今天就开始吧！只需访问linkedin.com即可免费发布您的职位。教授，您认为
doac what is the most important thing we
我们应该讨论但尚未讨论的最重要的事情是什么？
Professor that's my formal way to trust
教授，这是我委婉的说法，相信
me I think we've covered an awful
我。我认为我们已经讨论了
lot and I think the thing that I would
很多，我想
emphasize when people are thinking about
强调的是，当人们考虑
their health thinking about their diet
健康饮食时，
is firstly find what works for you MH
首先要找到适合自己的方法。 对于你来说，MH，
find something you
找到你
enjoy but I think I would say be really
喜欢的事情，但我认为你应该非常非常
really careful of the misinformation
小心那些错误信息，真的要非常小心。
careful and I would say also if you're
另外，如果你要
going to make a change make sure it has
做出改变，确保它的
a big enough size impact to Warrant the
影响足够大，值得
change you're making because there's a
你做出这样的改变。因为现在有
lot of advocates for this health
很多健康
optimization you know make this change
优化倡导者，他们会说做出这个改变就会
and it will have this impact well if
有这样的效果。但是，如果
you're making a change that disrupts
你做出的改变会
your life significantly but only has a
严重扰乱你的生活，却只对
you're interest in whether it's your
你关注的任何健康指标（无论是
cholesterol your own all energy or
胆固醇、精力还是
whatever is it really worth disrupting
其他方面）产生1%的影响，那么为了
your life that much for that small
这点微小的改变而如此大幅度地扰乱你的生活真的值得吗？
change and I think that's really
我认为这一点非常
important I hear so many times when I'm
重要。我经常
talking to other moms at schoolgate or
在学校门口或其他场合和其他妈妈聊天时听到她们说：“天哪，
that sort of thing oh my gosh I read
我读到
this and I'm going to do this and you
这个，我要去做这个，你
know it's going to be really hard but
知道这会非常难，但
they've said it will help with this and
他们说这会有帮助。”
it's like
这就好比，
oh you're taking way pleasure and
哦，你放弃了乐趣，
actually what is the
实际上，这样做有什么
gain and if the world is to move forward
好处呢？如果世界朝着
in a way that is positive in your
你
estimation how does the world change and
认为积极的方向发展，那又有什么意义呢？ 世界是否在改变和
improve as it relates to all the
改善，尤其是在
subjects we've talked about today what
我们今天讨论的所有主题方面？
is that change you wish to see in the
你希望在
world in which you
你
operate I would love to see a world
工作的环境中看到怎样的改变？我希望看到一个
where scientists food industry and
科学家、食品行业和
policy makers work together I'd love to
政策制定者携手合作的世界。我希望
see a world
看到一个
we encourage evidence-based science but
鼓励循证科学的世界，同时
scientists aren't scared of working with
科学家也不害怕与
food industry for example a lot of
食品行业合作。例如，很多
people think the food industry is bad
人认为食品行业很糟糕，
like it's this sort of evil guy who sat
就像一个坐在
in this boardroom who's just counting
会议室里的邪恶之人，只顾着数
money and just pushing whatever these
钱，把那些天真
little innocent children will put in
无邪的孩子们放进
their mouths and to make them addicted
嘴里的东西都推销给他们，让他们上瘾，导致
and give them neurod Divergence and all
神经发育不全、神经衰弱以及其他
kinds of other issues potentially a lot
各种问题。很多
of people feel that a lot of this the
人觉得
food industry has become this sort of
食品行业已经变成了一个
singular entity people think about in
单一的实体，就像
the sort of conspiracy theory internet
网络上那些阴谋论一样，
and you kind of imagine it is like a guy
你会想象它就像一个穿着
in a boardroom in a suit who's just like
西装的家伙坐在会议室里，
cackling and laughing and and stuff like
咯咯地笑着，诸如此类。
um I think
嗯，我觉得
that I can't comment on their
我无法评论他们的
motivations for profit um I don't think
逐利动机，我觉得
I'm informed enough to comment on that
我了解得还不够多，无法置评。 关于这一点，
but I do believe that the food industry
我确实认为食品行业
needs to work with Academia in order to
需要与学术界合作，才能
solve the problem of the kind of foods
解决市面上食品质量问题。
government though as well we need impact
当然，我们也需要政府的干预，需要
from policy makers we need to go back to
政策制定者的干预。我们需要回归
Grassroots we need to be educating our
基层，教育
children how to cook we need to be
孩子们如何烹饪，
giving healthy School meals we need to
提供健康的学校餐，
be educating them in schools what is a
在学校里教育他们什么是
healthy meal what isn't a healthy meal
健康餐，什么是不健康餐，
what is a healthy food but I think that
什么是健康食品。但我认为，
current state of fear I think I think
目前这种恐惧情绪非常重要。我认为
we're in a perilous State at the moment
我们正处于危险的境地。
some people making a lot of noise on in
有些人通过
the media about scientists working with
媒体大肆宣扬科学家与
industry how any research funded by
企业合作，声称任何由企业资助的研究都
industry is there bias it's corrupt
存在偏见、腐败、
can't be trusted that's certainly not my
不可信赖。但这绝对不是我的
experience it's not what I have ever
经验，我从未
seen from any other colleagues taking
见过其他同事接受
money from food industry in order to do
食品行业的资金进行
studies we as nutrition scientists need
研究。作为营养科学家，我们需要
to do studies we need to run clinical
进行研究，我们需要开展临床
trials in order to look at how we can
试验，以探索如何
improve the a few to make it healthier
改进食品，使其更健康。
the amount of funding we get from
我们从
independent government
独立政府
bodies it's tiny to get funding the
机构获得的资金数额有限。 获得资助非常困难，
amount of time we have to spend this
我们这些学者不得不花费大量时间
academics writing grants to be rejected
撰写研究经费申请，却屡屡
and rejected because the government
被拒，因为政府
invests so little in nutrition
对营养研究的投入实在太少。
research we need to be able to get
我们需要获得
funding to be able to run studies to
资金才能开展研究，
answer important questions the money and
解答重要的问题。就我
around me when we receive funding from
身边的人的经验而言，当我们从
research from when we receive funding
研究机构或企业获得资助时，
they are allowed to have with what we do
他们对我们的工作参与度非常有限。
and the university ensure that we
大学会确保我们
conduct the research we do the analysis
开展研究、进行分析并
we publish the paper the industry
发表论文。企业
funders cannot get involved in that
资助者不能参与这个
process so I still see it as
过程，所以我仍然认为它是
independent now there is discussion
独立的。现在有人讨论
about are they setting the agenda of
他们是否在设定研究议程，这确实是一个
we could talk about for days and days
可以讨论好几天的话题，
but I think this narrative that's out
但我认为那种认为
there that just because of studies being
研究因为接受
funded by the food industry is biased is
食品行业的资助就带有偏见的说法是
wrong and I think it's unhelpful and
错误的，而且我认为这种说法毫无益处。
it's putting these exposes that certain
某些
media p personalities are putting
媒体人士提出的这种观点，即
forward that if an academic has taken
如果一位学者接受了
money from a food industry that
食品行业的资助，那么
therefore they they cannot be advising
他们就不能就食品问题向
us on food they cannot be trusted for
我们提供建议，
their research I think that that's a
他们的研究也不可信，我认为这是一种错误的观念。
real problem for us as nutrition
对我们营养科学家来说，这确实是个问题，
scientists because it's
因为它
creating a time of fear MH
造成了恐慌。
yeah I mean of course so yeah when you
嗯，我的意思是，当然。当你
explain it through how these how these
解释这些
studies get funded then it makes a ton
研究是如何获得资助的时候，一切就都说得通了。
of sense and actually part of what I was
实际上，我一直在
thinking is the government should be
想，政府应该加大对
doing a little bit more to fund these
这类
kinds of studies because I can't I don't
研究的资助力度，因为我并不
really believe that you're going to get
相信
the food industry to work
食品行业会
together because again thinking about
齐心协力。想想
incentives if there's one serial company
激励机制，如果这里有一家连锁企业，那里有
here and the other here and say there's
另一家，假设有
10 of them um how can you get all of
十家，你怎么能让
them to agree to take yeah the two that
它们都同意参与呢？那些
don't win and then they keep their jobs
失败的公司保住了工作，而
companies are successful they get pats
成功的公司却得到了表扬。
on the back so when we think about
所以，当我们回顾
health interventions that the government
政府
have made over the years that been super
多年来采取的那些非常
effective they've come from like policy
有效的健康干预措施时，就会发现它们都源于政策，比如
smoking is a good example that I always
禁烟就是一个很好的例子。我一直认为……
think about like the change in smoking
想想
in our society because they made they
我们社会吸烟状况的变化，因为他们
banned smoking indoors and put things on
禁止室内吸烟，并在
the packaging and just change the sort
包装​​上印上相关规定，改变了
of social narrative and all smoking
社会舆论，所有
companies tobacco companies had to sort
烟草公司都必须立即
of comply at once so and that's why I
遵守。所以我
think all three have to work together
认为这三者必须合作，
government need to take big
政府需要承担重大
responsibility M now yeah and but I
责任。是的，我
think that there has to be an acceptance
认为必须接受
that academics scientists can work with
学术界和科学家可以与
food industry and it doesn't mean that
食品行业合作，这并不意味着
you're corrupt or corrup or are results
你腐败、受贿或存在任何
of bias in any
偏见。
way we have a closing tradition on this
我们这个播客有个结束语，上一位
podcast where the last guest leaves a
嘉宾会给下一位嘉宾留下一个
question for the next guest not knowing
问题，但不知道问题会留给
who they're leaving it for and the
谁。
question that's been left for you is
留给你的问题是：
what is something that you believe that
你认为
smart people you care about disagree
你关心的聪明人不同意的是什么？
with do you know what I believe I
你知道我的看法吗？我
believe that life can be simple that
相信生活可以很简单，
actually all that matters is that you
真正重要的是
have good
拥有良好的
relationships that you're finding joy in
人际关系，在生活中找到快乐，
life and that we shouldn't over
我们不应该把
complicate things and if on my
事情复杂化。如果我的
gravestone I have written Sarah was a
墓碑上写着“莎拉是个
person I would be very happy with that
好人”，我会非常高兴。
but a lot of the clever people are
但我认为很多聪明人
think wouldn't agree that that's
不会同意这种观点。 这
necessarily a good achievement in life
未必是人生中的一项成就，
but I see that as a great
但我认为这是一项伟大的
achievement what do you think they might
成就。你觉得他们会
want written on their gravestone
希望墓碑上刻什么呢？
instead you're smacking nervously I am
你紧张地拍着手。是的，是不是
is it that too obsessed with like impact
太执着于影响力
and ego and those kinds of things is
、自我之类的东西了？
that what you're saying
你是这个意思吗？
I don't know because the people I care
我不知道，因为我关心的人
about I don't think are
都不
egotistical I think we
自负。我认为我们
live in a society
生活在一个社会里，
certainly in a society where we're
尤其是在一个我们
mixing with successful people where
与成功人士交往的社会里，这里充满了
there is a lot of ambition where there
雄心壮志，
is a lot
非常
of um emphasis put on your
重视
achievements where there's a lot of
成就，大家都在努力追求下一个
striving for the next goal striving for
目标，
the next
下一个
achievement and and maybe it's having
成就。也许是因为
had four years where I took a career
我曾中断职业生涯四年，照顾
break where I was care of my mom and
我的母亲。
together with the rest of my family we
我和家人一起
looked after my mom we kept her at home
照顾她，让她待在家里，陪伴她度过
through a degenerative neurological
退行性神经系统疾病的折磨。
condition and seeing
看着一个人逐渐
someone change seeing someone lose the
失去
power to talk lose the power to eat lose
说话的能力、进食的能力、
the power to interact lose the power to
社交的能力，失去
do everything that we take for granted I
做所有我们习以为常的事情的能力，我
think has enabled me
想这让我
to not sweat the small stuff has enabled
不再为小事烦恼，让
me to find joy in most things pleasure
我找到了快乐。 在大多数情况下，享受
in most things and not strive
当下，而不是
for things that maybe in the past I
追求过去可能让我
have perspective I think it's given me a
有不同看法的东西。
perspective now don't get me wrong you
现在，我的想法发生了改变。别误会，你
know I you know I was nervous before
知道，来这里之前我很紧张，为此我焦虑不已。
and you know I'm not saying that I'm
我并不是说我
always like like horizontally laid back
一直都很放松，
means but I think it's given me a
但我认为这让我更清楚地
perspective on what matters to me yeah
认识到什么对我来说才是最重要的。是的，对我来说最重要的东西，
and what matters to me and I think the
我认为
greatest achievement in my whole life
我一生中最伟大的成就
has been actually not becoming Professor
其实是没能成为教授，
which I'm incredibly proud of I'm from a
我为此感到无比自豪。我来自一个
workingclass family you know I was the
工人阶级家庭，你知道，我是
first person in our family to ever go to
我们家第一个上
university my mom and dad didn't have
大学的人。我的父母没有
the privilege of staying at school
机会在
14 and I mean it saddens that they
14岁以后继续上学，我的意思是，他们
haven't seen this success saddens me
没能看到我取得这样的成就，这让我感到
very much and whilst The Pride I felt
非常难过。
yesterday at the ceremony was phenomenal
昨天在典礼上，我感到无比自豪，但
actually what I'm most proud of is the
实际上，我最引以为豪的是
four years that I cared for my
我照顾
mom and to me that's what
母亲的那四年，对我来说，这才是最重要的。所以，
matters and so that's why when I'm with
当我和
lots of smart people and I think they're
很多聪明人在一起，我认为他们正在
doing amazing things I don't have the
做的事情…… 真是不可思议的事情。
sometimes I've probably don't care as
有时候我的看法可能不太一样，我可能不太在意，
much as long as I'm having fun and do
只要我玩得开心就好。
you know what and I think I said this at
你知道吗？我想我一
the beginning I'm so privileged I get to
开始就说过，我很幸运能
do my hobby every day I love what I do
每天做自己喜欢的事情。我热爱我的工作。
I'm not doing this necessarily because
我做这件事不一定是因为
I'm such a a selfless person that I want
我是一个无私的人，想要
to improve everyone's Health yes if
改善每个人的健康。是的，如果
that's a byproduct great but I get up
这是个意外收获，那就太好了。但我每天起床都
and I love what I do I'm so
热爱我的工作，我为
excited by the science that we do and
我们所做的科学研究感到无比兴奋。
what drives me to do it is having been
驱使我这样做的原因是，我曾经历过
through that situation of realizing how
那种意识到
delicate life is so just use the moment
生命有多么脆弱的时刻。所以，珍惜当下，
enjoy what you're doing at that point in
享受你正在做的事情。非常
time thank you so much um Professor
感谢。教授，
congratulations on the professor didn't
祝贺您！我昨天没
realize it was uh you other ceremony
注意到您还有另一个颁奖典礼。那真是一项
yesterday that's an incredible
了不起的成就。
achievement I know that we're not we're
我知道我们现在不再像以前那样
not prioritizing the the achievements as
重视这些成就了，
much anymore but um incredible yeah it's
但是，嗯，这真的
it's incredible thing and it's a it's a
太棒了！这要
credit to the work that you've done and
归功于您所做的工作以及
how you've done it over the last 25
您完成工作的方式。 过去25
years and the broader impact I think
年以及更广泛的影响，我认为
you've had on so many millions of
您
people's lives now through now the
通过
content you produce but also all of the
您制作的内容以及
research that you've done firsthand so
您亲身进行的所有研究，对数百万人的生活产生了深远的影响。非常
thank you so much for doing the work
感谢您所做的工作，
that you do thank you for uh
感谢您
to me today I actually said a message to
今天为我阐明了这么多主题。我
my team before saying that um I've had
之前给我的团队发了条信息，说我之前也和
lots of conversations about nutrition
很多人讨论过营养
and stuff but the the primary research
之类的话题，但
you've done and the research you're
您所做的基础研究以及您正在进行的研究对
completely new to me and that's quite
我来说都是全新的，这对我来说相当
hard when when I sit here doing this
难得，因为我
every day so it's been a an absolute Joy
每天都在做同样的事情。所以，能
speaking to you and also not just from
和您交谈真是太荣幸了。这不仅是从
the information standpoint but from the
信息的角度，更是从更
broader philosophical idea of how one
广泛的哲学角度，从人们
should approach their life and how one
应该如何看待生活以及如何
can approach their life has been
看待生活的角度，都给了我
incredibly inspiring so thank you thank
极大的启发。非常感谢您，非常感谢
you it's been a real pleasure to talk
您。能和您谈论
about so many things I'm passionate
这么多我热衷的事情真是太好了，
about we shall do it again sometime
我们以后有机会再聊。
thank
谢谢。
you do you know that 80% of New Year's
您知道吗？80%的新年
resolutions fail by February it's
计划会在二月份就失败。 这是
because we focus too much on the end
因为我们太关注最终
goal and we forget the small daily
目标，而忽略了那些
actions that actually move us forward
真正推动我们前进的日常小行动。
also easy not to do in life it's easy to
生活中，那些容易做到的行动也容易被忽略。
save a dollar so it's also easy not to
省下一美元很容易，所以也很容易忽略
making one small Improvement each day
每天做出一点小小的改进。
one tiny step in the right direction has
朝着正确的方向迈出的一小步，
a big difference over time and that is
日积月累就能产生巨大的影响。这就是“
the 1% mindset which is why we created
1%思维”。正因如此，我们推出了“
the 1% diary a 90day journal designed to
1%日记”，这是一本为期90天的日志，旨在
help you stay consistent and focus on
帮助你保持自律，专注于
the small wins and make real progress
小小的胜利，并随着时间的推移取得真正的进步。
over time it also gives you access to
它还能让你加入“
the 1% Community a space where you can
1%社区”，在这里你可以
along with many others on the same
与许多其他志同道合的人一起，保持自律、获得动力和启发。
Journey we launched the 1% diary in
我们在11月推出了“1%日记”，
November and it sold out so now we're
并迅速售罄。现在我们
doing a second drop head Toth diary.com
进行第二次发售，请访问diary.com
to grab yours before it sells out again
抢购，以免再次售罄。
I'll put the link below
链接如下。
[Music]
[音乐]
a
a